<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remoting on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/tags/remoting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Remoting on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/tags/remoting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 12 – Using CredSSP for multi-hop authentication</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-12--using-credssp-for-multi-hop-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-12--using-credssp-for-multi-hop-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34;&gt;remoting series&lt;/a&gt;, we look at how &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc226764(PROT.10).aspx&#34;&gt;CredSSP &lt;/a&gt;can be used for &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ee309365(VS.85).aspx&#34;&gt;multi-hop authentication&lt;/a&gt; in PowerShell remoting. CredSSP and multi-hop support are not features of PowerShell 2.0 or PowerShell remoting, per se. Credential Security Service Provider (CredSSP) is a new security service provider that enables an application to delegate the user’s credentials from the client to the target server. Multi-hop support in Windows Remote Management uses CredSSP for authentication. Since PowerShell 2.0 remoting is built on top of WinRM, we can use CredSSP to perform multi-hop authentication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 11 – Interpreting, formatting and displaying remote output</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-11--interpreting-formatting-and-displaying-remote-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-11--interpreting-formatting-and-displaying-remote-output/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34;&gt;remoting series&lt;/a&gt;, we look at remoting output. This includes how the output is transferred from remote computer to local, how it is displayed and how we can format this output based on a need. We already discussed various methods to execute commands (&lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?p=1108&#34;&gt;part4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?p=1140&#34;&gt;part 5&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?p=1151&#34;&gt;part 6&lt;/a&gt;) on a remote computer. In this post, for the sake of our discussion of remoting output, I will use only Invoke-Command method to execute remote commands. However, I will point out the differences as required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 10 – Restricting available commands using custom session configuration</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-10--restricting-available-commands-using-custom-session-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-10--restricting-available-commands-using-custom-session-configuration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“With great power comes great responsibility”, said uncle Ben. But some people don’t just understand that. That is when you have to rip-off their powers. Similarly, the default PS Session configuration allows full access to PowerShell language, cmdlets, scripts and everything available to PowerShell. Of course, you need to authenticate as a local administrator or should have execute permission to invoke the session. Running a few cmdlets such as Stop-Service or Restart-Computer can be quite dangerous on a production server. This is where a custom session configuration can help provide role based access to remote host using PowerShell remoting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 9 – Session configurations and creating custom configurations</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-9--session-configurations-and-creating-custom-configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-9--session-configurations-and-creating-custom-configurations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In part2 of this series on &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34;&gt;PowerShell remoting &lt;/a&gt;we quickly looked at various cmdlets that form part of overall remoting infrastructure. The list there included cmdlets related to PS Session configuration. Now that we have gone through the basics of remoting, it is time for us to dig in to these additional cmdlets and explore what they really do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, in this part, we will look at all the PS session configurtion cmdlets, discuss how to create custom PS Session configurations and the need for it. Let us dive in to this now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 8 – remoting scenarios and troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-8--remoting-scenarios-and-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-8--remoting-scenarios-and-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following this remoting series and using PS remoting on a test setup or even production, you must have gone through a few initial hiccups. In fact, there could be many such issues if you are working in a mixed environment where you have a few computers in a domain and a few in workgroup. So, in this part of the remoting series I will discuss some of these issues and workarounds to resolve the same. I discussed enabling remoting on workgroup computers in &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?p=1060&#34;&gt;part3&lt;/a&gt; – “Enable remoting” of this series. This post is kind of an extension to that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 7 – saving remote session to disk</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-7--saving-remote-session-to-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-7--saving-remote-session-to-disk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?p=1151&#34;&gt;part 6&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34;&gt;remoting series&lt;/a&gt; we looked at how we can use Import-PSSession cmdlet to execute remote commands as if they were local. This is nice but this will last only while the session ($s in the example) is alive. The moment we kill the session — using Rem0ve-PSSession, remoting session will also get killed. In this part of the series, we will look at how we can save a remoting session to disk so that we don’t even have to explicitly create a session.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 6 – implicit remoting sessions</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-6-implicit-remoting-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-6-implicit-remoting-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier post on interactive remoting sessions, we looked at how we can enter a remote session and then execute commands as if they were local. However, if you’d observed it more closely, we were actually sitting in the remote session than local console. The change in PowerShell prompt indicates this fact clearly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34;&gt;remoting series&lt;/a&gt;, we will look at a feature called implicit remoting which makes it possible to run the commands / scripts on the remote computer while in the local session.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 5 – interactive remoting sessions</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-5-interactive-remoting-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-5-interactive-remoting-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34;&gt;remoting series&lt;/a&gt;, I will talk about using Enter-PSSession and Exit-PSSession cmdlets to perform interactive remoting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do you need interactive remoting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand the advantages of interactive remoting in PowerShell 2.0, let us first look at some gotchas with Invoke-Command. Take an example of a remote system where SharePoint 2010 is installed. SharePoint 2010 provides native PowerShell cmdlets and these cmdlets can be accesses only if you load Microsoft.SharePoint.PowerShell PS snap-in. So, to do this using Invoke-Command&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 4 – Execute commands or scripts on a remote computer using Invoke-Command</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-4--execute-commands-or-scripts-on-a-remote-computer-using-invoke-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-4--execute-commands-or-scripts-on-a-remote-computer-using-invoke-command/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this part of PowerShell &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;remoting series&lt;/a&gt;, I will discuss how to run commands or scripts on remote computer(s). Within remoting, there are couple of ways to run commands or scripts on a remote machine. This includes Invoke-Command cmdlet and interactive remoting sessions. These two methods deserve a separate post for each and hence I will discuss the Invoke-Command method in today&amp;rsquo;s post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?p=1060&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;enabled remoting&lt;/a&gt; on all your computers, you can use&lt;a href=&#34;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dd347578.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Invoke-Command&lt;/a&gt; cmdlet to run commands and scripts on local computer or on remote computer(s). There are many possible variations of this cmdlet. I will cover most of them here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 3 – Enable remoting</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-3--enable-remoting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-3--enable-remoting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34;&gt;series of articles&lt;/a&gt; on PowerShell 2.0 &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?cat=240&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;remoting&lt;/a&gt;, we will look at how to enable remoting in different scenarios. This post assumes that you are running a supported operating system and you have installed all necesary &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/?p=1025&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pre-requisite&lt;/a&gt; software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, how do you enable remoting?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remoting in PowerShell 2.0 can be enabled by just running the following cmdlet&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;enable-psremoting&#34;&gt;Enable-PSRemoting&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: You have to run this at a elevated PowerShell prompt. Also, all your active networks should be set to “Home” or “Work” network location. Setting firewall exceptions for remoting will fail if the network location is set to “Public”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 2 – Overview of remoting cmdlets</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-2--overview-of-remoting-cmdlets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-2--overview-of-remoting-cmdlets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In part 1 of this series I gave a quick introduction to PowerShell 2.0 remoting. Before we look at how to enable or configure a computer for remoting, let us take a quick look at PowerShell 2.0 remoting cmdlets. Here is a complete list of cmdlets with a brief overview.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list will also include cmdlets that are not directly used within remoting but help configure various aspects of remoting. The knowledge of these cmdlets such as WSMan, etc in this list is not mandatory for basic usage of PowerShell remoting. In this post, I will only discuss what each of these cmdlets are capable of and list any gotchas. A detailed usage of these cmdlets will be discussed later in the series.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 2.0 remoting guide: Part 1 – The basics</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-1-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-2-0-remoting-guide-part-1-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am starting a series of articles on remoting feature of PowerShell 2.0. This is one of the best features of PowerShell 2.0 and my favorite feature for sure. The number of very cool things one can achieve using this feature is just un-imaginable. I have started digging deep in to this feature as I start writing a network file browser powerpack as a part of hands-on. I hope it is worth sharing what I learn by writing about it here. So, this is the first in that series of posts. In this post, we will look at absolute basics to start using PowerShell remoting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
