<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Resource Manager on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/tags/azure-resource-manager/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure Resource Manager on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/tags/azure-resource-manager/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using secrets in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-secrets-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-secrets-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this series so far, you have seen how to get started with ARM templates, parameterize them by adding parameters, and optimize them using variables, expressions, and user-defined functions. It is now time to move on to more advanced topics and begin building the template for the remaining components of the architecture shown above. In the architecture shown above, you will implement an ARM template that provisions virtual machines, requiring the administrator and domain-join credentials as inputs. Also, the configuration scripts used to configure the guest OS may need to access an internal storage account blob, which requires the storage connection strings and access keys. Storing these secrets in plain text is not recommended. Also, as an architect, you may want to standardize on passwords for local administrator accounts and avoid sharing domain-join credentials with any user when provisioning an ARM template. This needs a more centralized credential and secret store. Azure Vault provides this capability. Today, you will learn how to handle secrets such as passwords, access keys, certificates, and more in an ARM template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using functions in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-functions-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-functions-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/&#34;&gt;Expressions in ARM template language&lt;/a&gt; are a way to reduce complexity in the templates. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/&#34;&gt;Using parameters and variables in ARM templates&lt;/a&gt; always requires the use of expressions. Parameter and variable values are combined with standard (built-in) template functions (STF) to create complex expressions to implement the business requirements and implement known configurations. Updated ARM template syntax introduced the ability to implement user-defined functions for complicated expressions and use repeatedly in your templates. In this part, you will learn more about standard template functions and learn how to implement user-defined functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using expressions and variables in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, you learned how to use VS Code and ARM Tools extension to get started with the ARM template development, how to perform a subscription scoped deployment to create a resource group and then looked at resource group scoped deployment to create a storage account and a virtual network resources. You learned about parameterizing the ARM template so that it becomes reusable. Equipped with that knowledge, you can now start digging into expressions and variables in the ARM templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Adding parameters to ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, you learned the template syntax and authored an ARM template that provisions the resource group needed for the above architecture. This deployment was performed at the subscription level using Azure CLI. In this part, you will create another template for performing additional resource &amp;ndash; storage account and virtual network &amp;ndash; provisioning at the resource group level. You will, then, parameterize this template to understand how to add parameters to ARM templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - ARM template basics</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last two parts of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;the series&lt;/a&gt;, you have seen a brief introduction to Azure Resource Manager and the services that complement ARM to extend its functionality or support the services offered by ARM. You also looked at an overview of ARM templates and the tools available to design, author, and deploy these templates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting this part of the series for the next few days, you will start learning about authoring ARM templates right from the basics and to the advanced template syntax and techniques with a goal to build an ARM template that helps provision the following architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Tools for ARM template design, authoring, and deployment</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-tools-for-arm-template-design-authoring-and-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-tools-for-arm-template-design-authoring-and-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of this series of articles on Azure Resource Manager (ARM) provided a quick overview of ARM. You looked a quick introduction to ARM templates as well and looked at an overview of different template deployment methods. In this part of the series, we will look at different methods to author ARM templates and an in-depth look at preferred deployment methods. You can choose any of the methods mentioned here but this series of articles will use one preferred method each for authoring and deploying templates. You will read more about those methods and the reasons behind that choice as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I had written a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/arm-templates/&#34;&gt;series of articles&lt;/a&gt; introducing and diving deep into authoring Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates. A few things have changed in authoring ARM templates and new features got added in the recent past. I thought it is probably a better time to revisit and do it all over again. At the same time, I thought why just limit to just authoring ARM templates. Over the years, I made notes around ARM and learned quite a bit. Starting today, I will share those notes with you here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Template Deployment Improvements in Azure Portal</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/custom-template-deployment-improvements-in-azure-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/custom-template-deployment-improvements-in-azure-portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When testing ARM templates, I typically use the custom template deployment option in the Azure Portal. This UI option just got better! This deployment option now supports lists the parameters, variables, and resources used in template in a nice treeview navigation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start a new deployment, you can click on New -&amp;gt; Template Deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate11-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate11-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This opens up the Custom Deployment blade. Click on Edit Template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Forcing WMF 4.0 when using DSC Extension</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-forcing-wmf-4-0-when-using-dsc-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-forcing-wmf-4-0-when-using-dsc-extension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This subject won&amp;rsquo;t really need a post of its own but I will do it anyway. In the previous part of this &lt;a href=&#34;http://azrs.tk/armseries&#34;&gt;ARM series&lt;/a&gt;, I showed how we can use the domain join extension instead of DSC to join a VM to an existing AD domain. This resulted is huge savings in time taken to deploy the entire scenario. When I was talking to my good friend, fellow PowerShell MVP and all-things-Azure guru, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bgelens&#34;&gt;Ben Gelens&lt;/a&gt;, he was quick to point that the delays when using DSC extension here could be due to the install of WMF 5.0. Indeed!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Domain Join Extension</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-domain-join-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-domain-join-extension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The scenario that we used to understand and build ARM templates contained a domain controller VM along with one or more VMs that joined the domain service hosted by the DC VM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate9-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate9-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make sure the VMs join the domain, we used PowerShell DSC configuration. One of the biggest quirks, at least what I faced, with DSC extension with ARM templates is that it takes little longer to complete. For example, the complete scenario deployment took almost 48 minutes to deploy. I am not making up that number. Here is the proof.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Putting it all together</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-putting-it-all-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-putting-it-all-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this series so far, we looked at building ARM templates by example. The focus was not really on the resource types or how to use resource definitions. Instead, our focus was on learning the basics of template language. To that extent, we have a scenario that we want to deploy and we are incrementally building the template for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate8-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate8-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While building an ARM template for this, we looked at how to use parameters and variables. We looked at using copy object to create multiple instances of a resource type without really writing the resource definition multiple times. We went on to find out how we can define dependencies between different resource types so they are orchestrated in the right order. We looked at how we can decompose the template into purpose-specific external templates and how to link them together. While learning these concepts, we created a template that almost built the scenario we started with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Linked Templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-linked-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-linked-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the ARM template authoring best practices is to decompose the JSON template, if applicable, into multiple target-specific templates. Think of this as creating re-usable code. You can leverage the re-usable parts of your code within multiple aspects of your application or the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For linking different external templates within the main template, we need to define the &lt;em&gt;Microsoft.Resources/deployments&lt;/em&gt; resource instance. Before we proceed let us look at the scenario for which we are building an ARM template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Defining Resource Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-defining-resource-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-defining-resource-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will continue learning about building ARM templates by looking at how we can define dependencies between resources. To recap, here is the scenario we are working on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate6-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate6-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the earlier parts of this series, we created the storage account, virtual network, a public IP, a load balancer, and added all inbound NAT rules required for the virtual machine RDP access. If you notice, we have components that depend on others. For example, the inbound NAT rules depend on the load balancer. Similarly, VMs depend on network interfaces which in turn depend on the virtual network. In the absence of dependencies, ARM will attempt to deploy these resources in parallel which may result in errors. So, within the resource template, we need to define these dependencies so that ARM can make decisions about the deployment sequence. There are multiple ways of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Copy Object</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-copy-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-copy-object/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are following this series, by now you know how to use parameters and variables in ARM template language. We used that knowledge to create a template that creates relevant things to like storage account and virtual network. Let us revisit the scenario.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate5-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate5-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part, we will extend the template to add publicIP, load balancer, and RDP endpoints for the virtual machines. Before we do that, let us review what we need. To achieve what we want in this, we will use copy object in the template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Variables</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-variables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following this series on &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/series/arm-templates/&#34;&gt;ARM templates&lt;/a&gt;, in the last part, we started with a sample scenario that we are using to build an ARM template. Here it is again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate4-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate4-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-parameters/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt;, we completed creation of storage account required for backing the OS and data disks for virtual machines in the deployment. The next step in our scenario is to create the virtual network for the VM connectivity. A virtual network and any subnets required must exist before the creation of virtual machines. So, in today’s article, we will see how we can use variables in the ARM template language while incrementally building an ARM template for our scenario and add virtual network. Towards the end, we will review some best practices guidance with regards to using parameters and variables in developing ARM templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Parameters</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-parameters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the earlier parts of this &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/series/arm-templates/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;, we briefly looked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-an-introduction/&#34;&gt;different methods of deploying ARM templates&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-the-basics/&#34;&gt;basics of ARM template language&lt;/a&gt;. Starting today’s article, we will see our leaning in action. To get going with our leaning, we will start building the ARM template for the following scenario.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate3-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armtemplate3-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will incrementally build this scenario by learning different aspects of ARM template language. We won’t be covering all resource types in Azure but we will cover every aspect of the ARM template language and functions and expressions used in the template language. We will also review best practices in building these ARM templates as we proceed forward in this series.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – The Basics</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a part of this series, we will go through the language semantics of writing ARM templates. We will explore each and every aspect of the ARM template language and go through multiple examples to understand the concepts better. We won’t focus much on the resource types and resource definitions until we complete the discussion around the language semantics and artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us get started.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;tools-for-the-job&#34;&gt;Tools for the job&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JSON templates for ARM can be edited in notepad too. But, there are better tools that can help us with this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-in/documentation/articles/resource-group-overview/&#34;&gt;Azure Resource Manager&lt;/a&gt; isn’t a new thing! It was announced during &lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2014/DEV-B224&#34;&gt;Build 2014&lt;/a&gt;. ARM is certainly the preferred way, with more and more services getting ARM support, to deploy Azure services. Microsoft also announced that the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fuAmcfmo3X0&#34;&gt;Azure Stack release&lt;/a&gt; will feature Azure Resource Manager and the template deployment. This means that learning how to use ARM and write you own templates is an essential skill not just for public cloud but also for the private and hybrid cloud administrators.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
