<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mcp on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/mcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mcp on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/mcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agent skills vs Model Context Protocol - [How] do you choose?</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/agent-skills-vs-model-context-protocol-how-do-you-choose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/agent-skills-vs-model-context-protocol-how-do-you-choose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anthropic &lt;a href=&#34;https://claude.com/blog/skills&#34;&gt;introduced Agent Skills&lt;/a&gt; in October 2025, just a year after they &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/news/model-context-protocol&#34;&gt;introduced Model Context Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (MCP). Today, both Agent Skills and MCP are open standards. The fact that a single company produced two standards that seem to be competing has fueled heated debate on social media, Hacker News, and developer blogs. Some claim that MCP is dead, while others argue that the comparison itself is moot. The truth is more nuanced than that. You can build powerful agents with either or both. For anyone building enterprise-grade agent-powered systems, understanding where these standards genuinely overlap, where they serve fundamentally different purposes, and where each falls short is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Model Context Protocol server for Azure</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-a-model-context-protocol-server-for-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-a-model-context-protocol-server-for-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/anthropic-model-context-protocol/&#34;&gt;earlier article&lt;/a&gt; in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/mcp/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; introduced Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s Model Context Protocol. It presented an example of building a simple MCP server for use with the Claude desktop application. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rchaganti/mcp-servers/tree/main/hello-world&#34;&gt;hello-world example&lt;/a&gt; was a very basic implementation of an MCP server. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we shall extend our knowledge of creating MCP servers to achieve more practical applications. We will build an MCP server to interact with Microsoft Azure resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anthropic made bootstrap MCP server development easy by providing the &lt;code&gt;create-mcp-server&lt;/code&gt; package. To get started, you need to install this locally as a tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model Context Protocol by Anthropic for connecting AI models to data</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/anthropic-model-context-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/anthropic-model-context-protocol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago, Anthropic introduced and open-sourced the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/news/model-context-protocol&#34;&gt;Model Context Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (MCP). MCP is the new standard for connecting AI models to external data sources and APIs more easily and consistently. With the advances in AI, models are becoming increasingly powerful in reasoning and quality. However, as text-completion machines, these models still lack access to real-time data. AI providers have worked around this using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) and tool calling. Every data source requires custom implementation, and every provider has a way of integrating tools with AI models. MCP addresses these silos by providing a universal, open standard for connecting AI systems with data sources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
