<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Local CI/CD for your Bicep templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-07-09-local-ci-cd-for-your-bicep-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-07-09-local-ci-cd-for-your-bicep-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the very important aspects of Infrastructure as Code (IaC) is automation. And, it is not just about the configuration tasks that we must automate but it is also the entire validation and deployment / delivery workflow itself. We call this a continuous integration (CI) and continuous delivery / deployment (CD) pipeline. The core idea of a CI/CD pipeline is to accelerate testing and uncover any bugs and fix those bugs before the code reaches production. There are many ways and tools to implement a CI/CD pipeline. We can use GitHub actions or Jenkins or AppVeyor to name just a few. But, as a starting point, I prefer building a local CI/CD pipeline using git hooks. In this article, I will show you how I built a simple test and deploy pipeline for my Azure Bicep experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Azure MVP Bootcamp – Microsoft Azure Cloud and DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-from-azure-mvp-bootcamp-microsoft-azure-cloud-and-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-from-azure-mvp-bootcamp-microsoft-azure-cloud-and-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege to join the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miraclesoft.com/&#34;&gt;Miracle &lt;/a&gt;team at Visakhapatnam today for an Azure MVP bootcamp. I spoke about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rchaganti/Presentations/tree/master/Azure-Boot-Camp-Vizag2016&#34;&gt;Microsoft Azure Cloud and DevOps&lt;/a&gt;. This event, I must say, it a very well organized and orchestrated. I have been to conferences and events in India and outside India and never seen this level of care of speakers and attendees anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started my day with a good morning walk along the beach and just loved it. I wish I get to do this often.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
