<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2A on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/a2a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2A on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/a2a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Framework Agent Communication: Microsoft Agent Framework meets Google ADK via A2A</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/cross-framework-agent-communication-microsoft-agent-framework-meets-google-adk-via-a2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/cross-framework-agent-communication-microsoft-agent-framework-meets-google-adk-via-a2a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-multi-agent-systems-with-google-adk-and-the-a2a-protocol/&#34;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;, we explored how to build multi-agent systems using Google&amp;rsquo;s Agent Development Kit (ADK) and the A2A (Agent-to-Agent) protocol. We built a currency conversion agent and exposed it via A2A, then created a travel assistant that consumed it—all within the ADK ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s where A2A truly shines: framework interoperability. The A2A protocol isn&amp;rsquo;t tied to any specific agent framework. Any A2A-compliant agent can communicate with any other, regardless of whether it was built with Google ADK, Microsoft Agent Framework, LangChain, or a custom implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building multi-agent systems with Google ADK and the A2A protocol</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-multi-agent-systems-with-google-adk-and-the-a2a-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-multi-agent-systems-with-google-adk-and-the-a2a-protocol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The landscape of AI agents is evolving rapidly, and one of the most significant developments is the emergence of standardized protocols that enable agents to communicate with one another. Google&amp;rsquo;s Agent Development Kit (ADK) natively supports the Agent-to-Agent (A2A) protocol, enabling developers to build sophisticated multi-agent systems where specialized agents can collaborate across network boundaries. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore what A2A is, why it matters, and walk through a complete implementation that demonstrates how to expose an agent as a remote service and consume it from another agent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
