<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oci on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/oci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oci on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/oci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building container images - using no tools</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-28-building-container-images-using-no-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-28-building-container-images-using-no-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a couple of earlier articles, we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-18-understanding-container-images-the-fundamentals/&#34;&gt;Linux constructs used in building container images&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-28-understanding-container-images-oci-image-specification/&#34;&gt;OCI image specification&lt;/a&gt; which standardizes the container image format. It is now time to understand how we can create container images. Knowing this is important to optimize the image size and building secure container images. And, of course, this knowledge also helps us appreciate what tools like Docker CLI or Buildah among many others help us achieve. There are many tools to build container images. We shall look at each of these methods in-depth in later parts of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/container-images/&#34;&gt;this series of articles&lt;/a&gt; on container images. For today, we will look into building container images using no tools! Actually, just using built-in OS tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containerization in Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-01-containerization-in-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-01-containerization-in-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Containerization is everywhere &amp;ndash; from on-premises data centers to the edge and in the cloud. We have been using containers right from development to production. I wrote about VS Code development containers and how &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/bicep-feature-in-vscode-devcontainer/&#34;&gt;I have standardized my development environment using devcontainers.&lt;/a&gt; There are several options for companies to run containerized applications in production. we can run individual application containers on a container host using engines like Docker. We can use tools like Docker &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/compose/&#34;&gt;Compose&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/swarm/&#34;&gt;Swarm&lt;/a&gt; for slightly complex multi-container, multi-host environments. However, it becomes complex to manage such environments. This needs us to implement a physical or virtualized server environment and handle all operational overhead associated with running our data center.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publish container images to Azure Container Registry</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-29-publish-container-images-to-azure-container-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-29-publish-container-images-to-azure-container-registry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/container-images/&#34;&gt;previous articles in this series&lt;/a&gt;, we looked at how to build container images and understand the OCI image specification that governs how the images are built and dealt with. Once the images are built, we may want to push them to a central repository for sharing with a larger community or a private container registry such as the Azure Container Registry (ACR).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we shall learn how to create an Azure Container Registry, push an image, and consume it back in the local environment. Let&amp;rsquo;s start!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding container images - OCI image specification</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-28-understanding-container-images-oci-image-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-28-understanding-container-images-oci-image-specification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-18-understanding-container-images-the-fundamentals/&#34;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;, we looked at how OverlayFS is used to work with container images. We learned how the image layers are associated with each other and how the copy-on-write layer gets created when a containers gets created from an image. Container registries such as Docker Hub and Quay offer container images for several popular applications and you can publish your images as well. There are different tools available to build and push images to container registries. Whatever container engine you use &amp;ndash; Docker or Podman &amp;ndash; you can simply pull the image [built using any tool] from the registry and use it. How is this interoperability made possible? The answer is the work &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencontainers.org/&#34;&gt;Open Container Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (OCI) is doing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding container images - The fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-18-understanding-container-images-the-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-18-understanding-container-images-the-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Containers have been around for a while. There is no need for an introduction to containers anymore but If you are still looking for some background, you can read a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/tags/containers/&#34;&gt;series of articles&lt;/a&gt; I have written on this blog. Docker simplified working with containers by introducing a way to package your applications and application dependencies as container images. It also provided the tooling that made running container instances from these images easy. This meant the user space tools abstracted all complex details and removed the need to know the inner workings of containers. Like every other technology, knowing the internals of how something is built becomes important when troubleshooting issues or optimizing what the technology does. And, of course, knowing / learning internals is fun too!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
