<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Bicep on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/tags/azure-bicep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure Bicep on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/tags/azure-bicep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fully automated Kubernetes cluster deployment on Azure in under 8 minutes</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-26-fully-automated-kubernetes-cluster-deployment-on-azure-in-under-8-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-26-fully-automated-kubernetes-cluster-deployment-on-azure-in-under-8-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier article, I wrote about provisioning a virtual Kubernetes cluster with kubeadm](&lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-13-installing-and-configuring-kubernetes-cluster-using-kubeadm-on-ubuntu/)&#34;&gt;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-13-installing-and-configuring-kubernetes-cluster-using-kubeadm-on-ubuntu/)&lt;/a&gt;. I use this method on a laptop with limited resources. This is good to a large extent but not good enough when I want to scale my experiments and learning. This is where I began planning my Kubernetes lab on Azure. I needed something I could spin quickly with no manual intervention. Given my interest in the Bicep language, I naturally wrote a Bicep template to perform this deployment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publish container images to Azure Container Registry</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-29-publish-container-images-to-azure-container-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-10-29-publish-container-images-to-azure-container-registry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/container-images/&#34;&gt;previous articles in this series&lt;/a&gt;, we looked at how to build container images and understand the OCI image specification that governs how the images are built and dealt with. Once the images are built, we may want to push them to a central repository for sharing with a larger community or a private container registry such as the Azure Container Registry (ACR).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we shall learn how to create an Azure Container Registry, push an image, and consume it back in the local environment. Let&amp;rsquo;s start!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides and Demo Scripts: Global Azure Bootcamp 2021 - Azure Bicep</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/slides-and-demo-scripts-introduction-to-azure-bicep-gab-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/slides-and-demo-scripts-introduction-to-azure-bicep-gab-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I had the opportunity to present live (virtually) at the Global Azure Bootcamp 2021. My session was around &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt;. I really enjoyed preparing for and delivering this session.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you follow me on Twitter or this blog, you know I&amp;rsquo;ve started a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-bicep&#34;&gt;new series of articles on Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt;. These articles are essentially notes from my Bicep learning sessions. There are a few more pending in the next few days, but overall, I really enjoyed learning about Bicep. This series and my session at GAB 2021 helped me share my learning with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieve and save Project Bicep examples from GitHub</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/retrieve-and-save-project-bicep-examples-from-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/retrieve-and-save-project-bicep-examples-from-github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Project Bicep&lt;/a&gt; aims to simplify how you author Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates. Bicep is a new declarative language and a transpiler. This transparent abstraction takes a bicep file and transpiles it into an ARM template JSON. The Bicep CLI provides the necessary capablities to compile bicep files to ARM templates and decompile ARM templates into bicep files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bicep language itself is very easy to understand and start using. However, as you start learning it may be helpful to see a few examples and draw some inspiration as you build your won bicep files. Project Bicep respository on GitHub has a good number of examples for varied level of complexity. While looking at these, I thought it may be a good idea to create scripts that can retrieve and save selected example locally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Global Azure Bootcamp India 2021</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/speaking-at-global-azure-bootcamp-india-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/speaking-at-global-azure-bootcamp-india-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://globalazure.net/&#34;&gt;Global Azure Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; is happening this year from April 15th to 17th as an online event. And, I will be speaking this year. I submitted a couple of sessions and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt; session got accepted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-is-azure-bicep&#34;&gt;So, what is Azure Bicep?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Bicep is the Domain-Specific Language (DSL) and a transparent abstraction built on top of Azure Resource Manager (ARM). The intention behind this project is to simplify authoring ARM templates. Bicep language transpiles into an ARM template JSON which you can deploy using already well-known methods and your existing CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
