<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Containers on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/series/containers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Containers on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravikanthchaganti.com/series/containers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Devcontainers for cloud-native application development</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/devcontainers-for-cloud-native-application-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/devcontainers-for-cloud-native-application-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Containers changed the way we develop, package, and distribute applications. This helped teams accelerate development and ensure their code worked consistently across different environments and infrastructures. To a large extent, this enabled write once and run anywhere. Docker made this easy by providing tools to create, manage, and package application code and dependencies as images. We could run a container instance from that image wherever a container runtime exists. Standardizing image and runtime formats helped ensure we could take an image and run it anywhere and not worry about the underlying infrastructure. This also led to the proliferation of microservices-based application architectures, where an application comprises several services running within containers to deliver the expected functionality. Most cloud-native and modern application architectures use microservices to implement the necessary functionality. When developing an application with multiple microservice dependencies, a developer must ensure the development environment is suitably set up to handle all required dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and using Azure Container Instances service - Multi-container Applications using Bicep</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-03-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-multi-container-apps-using-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-03-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-multi-container-apps-using-bicep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous article, we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/&#34;&gt;getting started with Azure Container Instances service&lt;/a&gt;, learned some basic concepts of ACI, and saw an example of provisioning a hello-world application. In this article, we shall extend this knowledge by provisioning a multi-container application to ACI using Bicep templates. You can also use a YAML method of provisioning multi-container applications to ACI. We shall look at this later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we learned earlier, a container group resembles a Kubernetes pod. The containers within the group share resources such as network and storage. The resource usage of containers can be controlled at the container group level. As a general rule of thumb, we should group containers with similar lifecycle and resource requirements into a container group. The multi-container groups are available for Linux containers only at the moment. Based on the region, there will be additional restrictions in terms of resource allocation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and using Azure Container Instances service - The Basics</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier article, we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-01-containerization-in-azure&#34;&gt;different containerization options&lt;/a&gt; in Microsoft Azure. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we shall start with Azure Container Instances (ACI) and learn the fundamentals. In a later article, we will learn how to perform multi-container applications to ACI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;azure-container-instances&#34;&gt;Azure Container Instances&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Container Instances (ACI) service offers a quick and easy way to run containers in the Microsoft Azure cloud. It is as simple as running a container locally using the Docker engine. ACI does not provide full container orchestration. ACI is great for applications that require faster startup times and hassle-free management. ACI runs inside Azure VMs and therefore provides isolation enabled by virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containers – What are they? And, their history! – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/containers-what-are-they-and-their-history-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/containers-what-are-they-and-their-history-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the earlier article, I explained the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/containers-what-are-they-why-do-you-need-one-part-1&#34;&gt;hurdles in the traditional and virtualized ways of implementing workloads&lt;/a&gt;. Also, we looked how the DevOps challenges are demanding changes the continuous delivery and integration processes. Towards the end, I’d mentioned that Containers are an answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s article, we will see what are containers and some history behind containerization. Let us get started. In the subsequent parts, we will dig into each building block used within container technologies and understand how to use them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containers – What are they? Why do you need one? – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/containers-what-are-they-why-do-you-need-one-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/containers-what-are-they-why-do-you-need-one-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Containers? No, not the shipping containers but the much-hyped container technology in the computer industry. I am sure even if you have not used any of the existing container technologies, you must have at least read or heard about them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not the first one to write about containers and this is certainly not an in-depth overview of container technologies. I will eventually get there and show you how you can deploy different container technologies. This series of articles is about my own thoughts and a documentation for my own reference. In the process, I wish to help my readers as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
