<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PowerShell Secret Management on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/series/powershell-secret-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PowerShell Secret Management on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/series/powershell-secret-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell and Secret Management - Updates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-and-secrets-management-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-and-secrets-management-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the recent Ignite event, Microsoft announced the release candidate 2 update of PowerShell &lt;code&gt;SecretManagement&lt;/code&gt; module and the &lt;code&gt;SecretStore&lt;/code&gt; extension vault modules. Both modules have been bumped up to version 0.9.1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the updated release, the secret management module has added support for secret metadata. The extension vault module must implement support for the metadata for this to work. To this extent, the SecretStore module has been updated to support metadata as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell and Secret Management - Using Secret Store Extension Vault</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-and-secret-management-using-secret-store-extension-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-and-secret-management-using-secret-store-extension-vault/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: This article has been updated to show the latest version of the secret store module.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last part, you have seen an introduction to secret management in PowerShell and towards the end you learned that they are vault extensions that provide the real functionality for storing and managing secrets. In this part of the series, you will learn more about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/Microsoft.PowerShell.SecretStore&#34;&gt;SecretStore&lt;/a&gt; vault extension for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/Microsoft.PowerShell.SecretManagement&#34;&gt;SecretManagement&lt;/a&gt; PowerShell module.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The SecretStore extension vault is a wrapper around the .NET Crypto API. This vault stores the secrets to the local machine based on the current user account context. You can install this from the PowerShell gallery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell and Secret Management - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-and-secret-management-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-and-secret-management-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: This article has been updated to show the latest version of the secret management module.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within the infrastructure automation, you always stumble upon a need to store and retrieve credentials. For example, imagine deploying a database instance and you want the database administrator username and password to be same across based on some IT standard. For this, you either have to hardcode the values in a script or prompt the user running the automation for these values. Storing secrets such as passwords, API keys, etc is a big NO. You should never do that. And, prompting a user will hamper the automation flow and will require manual intervention. This is where secret vaults play a role. You can store all secrets in a vault (local or remote) and then on-demand you can retrieve these values from the vault and consume in your automation. This method is most preferred when delegating automation tasks, running scripts in CI / CD pipelines, and in general anything that requires unattended automation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
