<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflows on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/workflows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflows on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/workflows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Handoff workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/handoff-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/handoff-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous articles, we explored Sequential and Concurrent workflow patterns in the Microsoft Agent Framework (MAF). Today, we dive into one of the most practical and widely-applicable patterns: the handoff workflow. The handoff pattern models real-world scenarios in which a conversation or task is transferred from one agent to another based on context, expertise, or role. Think of it like a customer support call center—you first speak with a frontline agent who assesses your issue and then routes you to the appropriate specialist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concurrent workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/concurrent-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/concurrent-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the [previous article](&lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/sequential-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/&#34;&gt;Sequential workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework | Ravikanth Chaganti&lt;/a&gt;), we explored the sequential workflow pattern, a straightforward approach where agents process tasks one after another in a defined order. While sequential workflows are powerful for pipeline-style processing, they have a limitation: speed. When agents don&amp;rsquo;t depend on each other&amp;rsquo;s output, running them one at a time is inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where the concurrent workflow pattern comes into play. This pattern allows multiple agents to work in parallel, dramatically reducing total execution time and enabling scenarios that require diverse perspectives to be analyzed simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/sequential-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/sequential-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A single AI agent is powerful and can do impressive things. But real-world applications often need multiple specialists working together, with each agent handling a specific task before passing results to the next. As with humans, in the agentic world we also need to break complex problems into manageable pieces and have specialized agents handle each task. We need one agent to review another&amp;rsquo;s work and handle complex tool invocation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
