<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflows on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/workflows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflows on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/workflows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Magentic workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/magentic-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/magentic-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seems like a season of &lt;a href=&#34;https://agentskills.io/home&#34;&gt;Agent Skills&lt;/a&gt; adoption. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/google-adk-agent-skills/&#34;&gt;Google ADK implemented support for skills&lt;/a&gt; a couple of weeks ago, and it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/agent-framework/pull/4210&#34;&gt;Microsoft Agent Framework&amp;rsquo;s turn last week&lt;/a&gt;. In an earlier article in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/google-adk/&#34;&gt;Google ADK series&lt;/a&gt;, we implemented an IaC agent that leverages skills for generating Bicep templates that comply with organizational policies. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we will explore how to implement the same in Microsoft Agent Framework (MAF).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike Google ADK, MAF has no inline skill support, so all skills must be implemented as directory skills. We will equip our agent with two skills:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magentic workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/magentic-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/magentic-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this series on Microsoft Agent Framework (MAF), we&amp;rsquo;ve explored &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/sequential-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/&#34;&gt;sequential workflows&lt;/a&gt; where agents process tasks in a fixed order, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/concurrent-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/&#34;&gt;concurrent workflows&lt;/a&gt; where agents work in parallel, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/handoff-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/&#34;&gt;handoff workflows&lt;/a&gt; where agents transfer control based on context, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/group-chat-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/&#34;&gt;group chat workflows&lt;/a&gt; where agents engage in turn-based discussions. Each pattern has its strengths, but they all share one limitation: the orchestration logic is predetermined at design time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What if you need a workflow that can adapt its routing decisions based on what agents discover during execution? Enter Magentic workflows, the most sophisticated orchestration pattern in MAF, where an LLM-powered manager autonomously coordinates specialized agents, making real-time decisions about who to invoke next based on intermediate results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group chat workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/group-chat-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/group-chat-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous articles of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/microsoft-agent-framework/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;, we explored three powerful workflow patterns in Microsoft Agent Framework (MAF):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sequential: Agents process in a fixed order, like a pipeline.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Concurrent: Agents work in parallel, with results aggregated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Handoff: A coordinator routes requests to specialist agents.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what happens when you need agents to discuss, debate, and build on each other&amp;rsquo;s ideas, like a brainstorming session or a committee meeting? This is where the &lt;code&gt;GroupChat&lt;/code&gt; workflow pattern shines. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to build dynamic multi-agent conversations using &lt;code&gt;GroupChatBuilder&lt;/code&gt;, where a moderator (or selection function) orchestrates turn-based discussions among participant agents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handoff workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/handoff-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/handoff-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous articles, we explored Sequential and Concurrent workflow patterns in the Microsoft Agent Framework (MAF). Today, we dive into one of the most practical and widely-applicable patterns: the handoff workflow. The handoff pattern models real-world scenarios in which a conversation or task is transferred from one agent to another based on context, expertise, or role. Think of it like a customer support call center—you first speak with a frontline agent who assesses your issue and then routes you to the appropriate specialist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concurrent workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/concurrent-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/concurrent-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the [previous article](&lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/sequential-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/&#34;&gt;Sequential workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework | Ravikanth Chaganti&lt;/a&gt;), we explored the sequential workflow pattern, a straightforward approach where agents process tasks one after another in a defined order. While sequential workflows are powerful for pipeline-style processing, they have a limitation: speed. When agents don&amp;rsquo;t depend on each other&amp;rsquo;s output, running them one at a time is inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where the concurrent workflow pattern comes into play. This pattern allows multiple agents to work in parallel, dramatically reducing total execution time and enabling scenarios that require diverse perspectives to be analyzed simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/sequential-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/sequential-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A single AI agent is powerful and can do impressive things. But real-world applications often need multiple specialists working together, with each agent handling a specific task before passing results to the next. As with humans, in the agentic world we also need to break complex problems into manageable pieces and have specialized agents handle each task. We need one agent to review another&amp;rsquo;s work and handle complex tool invocation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
