<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Devcontainers for cloud-native application development</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/devcontainers-for-cloud-native-application-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/devcontainers-for-cloud-native-application-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Containers changed the way we develop, package, and distribute applications. This helped teams accelerate development and ensure their code worked consistently across different environments and infrastructures. To a large extent, this enabled write once and run anywhere. Docker made this easy by providing tools to create, manage, and package application code and dependencies as images. We could run a container instance from that image wherever a container runtime exists. Standardizing image and runtime formats helped ensure we could take an image and run it anywhere and not worry about the underlying infrastructure. This also led to the proliferation of microservices-based application architectures, where an application comprises several services running within containers to deliver the expected functionality. Most cloud-native and modern application architectures use microservices to implement the necessary functionality. When developing an application with multiple microservice dependencies, a developer must ensure the development environment is suitably set up to handle all required dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Container Image</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/bicep-container-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/bicep-container-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/_/microsoft-azure-cli&#34;&gt;Azure CLI container image&lt;/a&gt; for one of my side projects, I started looking for an image that contains Bicep CLI as well. I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/miqm&#34;&gt;Mikolaj Mackowiak&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/miqm/bicep-cli&#34;&gt;Bicep-cli image&lt;/a&gt;. This was what I really needed and it includes both Azure CLI and Bicep CLI. However, just as a fun side project, I wanted to publish my own image as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
