<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cagent on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/cagent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cagent on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/cagent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker cagent - An introduction</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/docker-cagent-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/docker-cagent-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker is one company that has been really taking advantage of the AI wave. True to its philosophy, it is helping developers with new tools and frameworks to simplify AI application development. Starting with Docker MCP catalog, MCP toolkit, Model Runner, MCP gateway, and cagent, Docker is certainly at the forefront of AI agent developer experience. In this article, we will get started with &lt;code&gt;cagent&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/blog/cagent-build-and-distribute-ai-agents-and-workflows/&#34;&gt;Docker &lt;code&gt;cagent&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/cagent&#34;&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt;, multi-agent AI runtime that lets you build, orchestrate, and share teams of specialized AI agents defined declaratively in YAML. Instead of wiring together complex agent frameworks in code, you describe what each agent does, which tools it can access, and how agents delegate to one another. &lt;code&gt;cagent&lt;/code&gt; handles the rest: model communication, tool orchestration, context isolation, and inter-agent coordination. It ships bundled with Docker Desktop 4.49+ and can distribute agent configurations as OCI artifacts through Docker Hub, treating agents with the same rigor as container images. Written in Go and currently labeled experimental, &lt;code&gt;cagent&lt;/code&gt; represents Docker&amp;rsquo;s bet that the agent ecosystem needs the same standardization, portability, and trust infrastructure that containers brought to application deployment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
