<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Policy on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/azure-policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure Policy on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/azure-policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Guest Configuration - Assignments</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-assignments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-introduction/&#34;&gt;last part of this series&lt;/a&gt; around &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-policy-guest-configuration/&#34;&gt;Azure Policy Guest Configuration&lt;/a&gt;, you got an introduction to what is Guest Configuration. In this part, you will learn about assigning Guest Configuration policies and initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Policy Guest Configuration (GC) is an extension to Azure Policy and therefore use the same JSON definition structure. For example, here is the (redacted) GC definition for the policy &lt;em&gt;Audit Windows machines that do not have the specified Windows PowerShell execution policy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Guest Configuration - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As your Azure adoption increases and as you on-board various departments and groups within your organization to start using Azure services, it is important that you put in place some level of governance. As cloud architect, you would want control over who can create what type resources, where can they create those resources and how many. You would also want to standardize on the deployments so that the configuration of resources is in compliance with your organization standards. Among many other aspects like this you would want the ability to track your cloud cost more granularly for every service deployed in the cloud and for every business unit or group within your organization. To address this and to implement efficient governance Azure offers features and services such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/policy/overview&#34;&gt;Policies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/management-groups/&#34;&gt;Management Groups&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/features/resource-graph/&#34;&gt;Resource Graph&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/blueprints/overview&#34;&gt;Blueprints&lt;/a&gt;. Here is an excellent depiction of Azure governance architecture from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/us-partner-blog/2019/07/24/azure-governance/&#34;&gt;partner blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
