<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing a self-paced learning platform and preview of LearnCTL</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/announcing-a-self-paced-learning-platform-and-preview-of-learnctl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/announcing-a-self-paced-learning-platform-and-preview-of-learnctl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The beginning of 2026 also marks the start of my 26th year in the IT industry. Being an 80s kid and having joined the IT industry in the early 2000s, I have seen and experienced different waves of computing, from bare-metal systems to virtualization, to containers and Kubernetes, to generative AI. I was fortunate to participate in and contribute to each of these waves of computing. My work at Wipro and Dell Technologies enabled me in this journey. This was a great learning experience, and applying those skills at work is the most satisfying part. Outside my role at these companies, I benefited immensely from online and offline technical communities. I have learned from many experts in several areas. At the same time, I started giving back to the community. I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://powershellmagazine.com&#34;&gt;PowerShell Magazine&lt;/a&gt; back in 2011, and while it was at the top of the game, it provided the most in-depth technical content to help the PowerShell community learn. I moved on from PowerShell as a tool for automation and started focusing on Linux, containers, Kubernetes, and eventually on Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
