<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitHub on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitHub on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Hub CLI - An extension to git command-line</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/github-hub-cli-an-extension-to-git-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/github-hub-cli-an-extension-to-git-command-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I started writing more in markdown and using GitHub pages, my work with git and GitHub increased quite a bit. At times, I find myself fighting with git conflicts and merges. I am not an expert in git command-line and in a complex scenario, I figure my way out looking for some help.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may have already seen in my articles that I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://cli.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub CLI&lt;/a&gt; a lot to work with my GitHub repositories, pull requests, and issues. I recently started using another CLI tool from GitHub called &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.github.com/&#34;&gt;hub&lt;/a&gt;. Hub is an extension to git command-line and makes working with GitHub from the command-line a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell commands to generate Git.io shorturls</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-commands-to-generate-git-io-shorturls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/powershell-commands-to-generate-git-io-shorturls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 660; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/gitio.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git.io&#34;&gt;Git.io&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; service by GitHub &amp;ndash; can be used generate the short URLs for any GitHub.com based URL. You can navigate to Git.io and paste a GitHub URL into the input box and generate a short URL. Note that this works only with GitHub.com URLs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gist.github.com/&#34;&gt;gists&lt;/a&gt; a lot lately and the URL to gists is usually very long and includes guids. For these gist URLs, I have been using the git.io service and wrapped that in a quick PowerShell module to help me generate these URLs. Today, I published it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rchaganti/psgitio&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/psgitio/1.0.0.0&#34;&gt;PowerShell Gallery&lt;/a&gt; for you to use it as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub workflow for streamlined publishing of static pages</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/github-workflow-for-streamlined-publishing-of-static-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/github-workflow-for-streamlined-publishing-of-static-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I moved to this site/blog to static pages using Hugo and GitHub pages, I have been finding ways to optimize the publishing experience. If you ever used Wordpress, the plugins that are available to customize the site look and feel and functionality will spoil you. They make your life easy by extending base functionality and you can achieve pretty much anything you want as long as there is a plugin for that and you will always find one. Moving from such an environment to a static page generator makes you feel that you have to do all the heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I use GitHub Gists to store and display code snippets in blog posts</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/how-i-use-gists-to-store-and-display-code-snippets-in-blog-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/how-i-use-gists-to-store-and-display-code-snippets-in-blog-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After I moved to a static site hosted on GitHub Pages, I was looking at different options to share the code snippets in a better way. With the Hugo generated static pages, there are a few options for code sharing in an article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use the simple pre-formatted text in markdown. This is usually done by enclosing code snippet in ```. This appears (in Hugo Coder theme I am using) as a big black block and has no way to choose the right syntax highlighting based on what programming language the snippet is written in. There are no line numbers or no highlighting of lines in a code snippet and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moved Blog to a Static Site Using Hugo and GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/moved-to-static-site-using-hugo-and-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/moved-to-static-site-using-hugo-and-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 50%; height: 50%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/welcome.jpg&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34; style=&#34;display: block; height: 100%;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/welcome.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: 100%; object-fit: cover; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I wrote something here. I was using a Digital Ocean droplet to run this blog using self-hosted version of Wordpress. Overall, it was good experience but there are issues with Wordpress installs. While it allows greater levels of customization, when all you need is just sharing your ideas, it becomes rather heavy. Also, the recent vulnerabilities made me think about it again. While I was having this thought process, I came across a few sites hosted on GitHub pages using Jekyll and simple static pages. I really wanted to move but moving from Wordpress to static site isn&amp;rsquo;t an easy option. There are Wordpress &lt;a href=&#34;https://ma.ttias.be/step-by-step-guide-migrating-wordpress-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;plugins available to export&lt;/a&gt; to markdown format and then host the same on GitHub pages. This is done using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. While, on paper, it looks very easy job, it is actually not. The exported markdown files won&amp;rsquo;t be compatible with your selected &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo theme&lt;/a&gt;. As I was wondering about this whole process, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChendrayanV&#34;&gt;Chen&lt;/a&gt; came to the rescue and gave me a head start. After reviewing what he sent and doing some more research, I decided to build the site from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
