<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Key Vault on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/key-vault/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Key Vault on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/key-vault/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using secrets in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-secrets-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-secrets-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this series so far, you have seen how to get started with ARM templates, parameterize them by adding parameters, and optimize them using variables, expressions, and user-defined functions. It is now time to move on to more advanced topics and begin building the template for the remaining components of the architecture shown above. In the architecture shown above, you will implement an ARM template that provisions virtual machines, requiring the administrator and domain-join credentials as inputs. Also, the configuration scripts used to configure the guest OS may need to access an internal storage account blob, which requires the storage connection strings and access keys. Storing these secrets in plain text is not recommended. Also, as an architect, you may want to standardize on passwords for local administrator accounts and avoid sharing domain-join credentials with any user when provisioning an ARM template. This needs a more centralized credential and secret store. Azure Vault provides this capability. Today, you will learn how to handle secrets such as passwords, access keys, certificates, and more in an ARM template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
