<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aci on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/tags/aci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aci on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/tags/aci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and using Azure Container Instances service - Multi-container Applications using Bicep</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-03-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-multi-container-apps-using-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-03-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-multi-container-apps-using-bicep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous article, we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/&#34;&gt;getting started with Azure Container Instances service&lt;/a&gt;, learned some basic concepts of ACI, and saw an example of provisioning a hello-world application. In this article, we shall extend this knowledge by provisioning a multi-container application to ACI using Bicep templates. You can also use a YAML method of provisioning multi-container applications to ACI. We shall look at this later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we learned earlier, a container group resembles a Kubernetes pod. The containers within the group share resources such as network and storage. The resource usage of containers can be controlled at the container group level. As a general rule of thumb, we should group containers with similar lifecycle and resource requirements into a container group. The multi-container groups are available for Linux containers only at the moment. Based on the region, there will be additional restrictions in terms of resource allocation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and using Azure Container Instances service - The Basics</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier article, we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-01-containerization-in-azure&#34;&gt;different containerization options&lt;/a&gt; in Microsoft Azure. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we shall start with Azure Container Instances (ACI) and learn the fundamentals. In a later article, we will learn how to perform multi-container applications to ACI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;azure-container-instances&#34;&gt;Azure Container Instances&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Container Instances (ACI) service offers a quick and easy way to run containers in the Microsoft Azure cloud. It is as simple as running a container locally using the Docker engine. ACI does not provide full container orchestration. ACI is great for applications that require faster startup times and hassle-free management. ACI runs inside Azure VMs and therefore provides isolation enabled by virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
