<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AzCli on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/azcli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AzCli on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/azcli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Global Azure Bootcamp - Azure CLI 2.0</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-and-demo-scripts-from-azure-cli-2-0-tips-and-tricks-session-at-globalazurebootcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-and-demo-scripts-from-azure-cli-2-0-tips-and-tricks-session-at-globalazurebootcamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity over the weekend to speak at the Global Azure Bootcamp organized by local Microsoft user groups. This event was held at ABB office in Bangalore and I must say that they have done a splendid job. It was a very well organized event. I had only one session and it was about Azure CLI 2.0 Tips and Tricks. I mentioned earlier that I am using CLI mostly these days to work with Azure resources and in this session I shared some tips and tricks around making it easier to work with Azure resource management using Azure CLI 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Experts Live India – Azure at the command line</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/session-slides-experts-live-india-azure-at-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/session-slides-experts-live-india-azure-at-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to speak at the inaugural edition of Experts Live India 2019 over the weekend. It was a great experience. The organizers did a great job even when there were teething facilities issues that plagued the event right from the start.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first session was on Azure at the command line. In this session, I walked through both Az CLI 2.0 and Az PowerShell modules and explained the differences to help the audience choose the right tool for their job. The slides do not contain a huge deal of information as I preferred showing the audience a good demo to understand the differences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
