<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ARM Template on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/tags/arm-template/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ARM Template on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/tags/arm-template/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using secrets in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-secrets-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-secrets-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this series so far, you have seen how to get started with ARM templates, parameterize them by adding parameters, and optimize them using variables, expressions, and user-defined functions. It is now time to move on to more advanced topics and begin building the template for the remaining components of the architecture shown above. In the architecture shown above, you will implement an ARM template that provisions virtual machines, requiring the administrator and domain-join credentials as inputs. Also, the configuration scripts used to configure the guest OS may need to access an internal storage account blob, which requires the storage connection strings and access keys. Storing these secrets in plain text is not recommended. Also, as an architect, you may want to standardize on passwords for local administrator accounts and avoid sharing domain-join credentials with any user when provisioning an ARM template. This needs a more centralized credential and secret store. Azure Vault provides this capability. Today, you will learn how to handle secrets such as passwords, access keys, certificates, and more in an ARM template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using functions in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-functions-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-functions-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/&#34;&gt;Expressions in ARM template language&lt;/a&gt; are a way to reduce complexity in the templates. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/&#34;&gt;Using parameters and variables in ARM templates&lt;/a&gt; always requires the use of expressions. Parameter and variable values are combined with standard (built-in) template functions (STF) to create complex expressions to implement the business requirements and implement known configurations. Updated ARM template syntax introduced the ability to implement user-defined functions for complicated expressions and use repeatedly in your templates. In this part, you will learn more about standard template functions and learn how to implement user-defined functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using expressions and variables in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, you learned how to use VS Code and ARM Tools extension to get started with the ARM template development, how to perform a subscription scoped deployment to create a resource group and then looked at resource group scoped deployment to create a storage account and a virtual network resources. You learned about parameterizing the ARM template so that it becomes reusable. Equipped with that knowledge, you can now start digging into expressions and variables in the ARM templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Adding parameters to ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, you learned the template syntax and authored an ARM template that provisions the resource group needed for the above architecture. This deployment was performed at the subscription level using Azure CLI. In this part, you will create another template for performing additional resource &amp;ndash; storage account and virtual network &amp;ndash; provisioning at the resource group level. You will, then, parameterize this template to understand how to add parameters to ARM templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - ARM template basics</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last two parts of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;the series&lt;/a&gt;, you have seen a brief introduction to Azure Resource Manager and the services that complement ARM to extend its functionality or support the services offered by ARM. You also looked at an overview of ARM templates and the tools available to design, author, and deploy these templates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting this part of the series for the next few days, you will start learning about authoring ARM templates right from the basics and to the advanced template syntax and techniques with a goal to build an ARM template that helps provision the following architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Tools for ARM template design, authoring, and deployment</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-tools-for-arm-template-design-authoring-and-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-tools-for-arm-template-design-authoring-and-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of this series of articles on Azure Resource Manager (ARM) provided a quick overview of ARM. You looked a quick introduction to ARM templates as well and looked at an overview of different template deployment methods. In this part of the series, we will look at different methods to author ARM templates and an in-depth look at preferred deployment methods. You can choose any of the methods mentioned here but this series of articles will use one preferred method each for authoring and deploying templates. You will read more about those methods and the reasons behind that choice as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
