<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Book] Azure Bicep - Zero to Hero is complete</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-07-09-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero-s-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-07-09-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero-s-complete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally! I published the final chapter in my book &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/azurebicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep - Zero to Hero&lt;/a&gt; today. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/book-announcing-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero/&#34;&gt;started this project more than a year ago&lt;/a&gt; with an intention that I will complete it before end of year 2021. However, a few personal life events made me shift focus to my family and that pushed the book timelines to the right. In the last few weeks, I spent good amount of my personal time to explore a few new areas within Bicep and formed the content for the last few chapters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Book] - Annoucing Azure Bicep - Zero to Hero</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/book-announcing-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/book-announcing-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many are struggling to make ends meet ever since the pandemic started. Therefore, I decided that all proceeds from this book will go to charity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Project Bicep&lt;/a&gt; is undoubtedly the best thing that happened in the Azure world, and I have been following the development and using Bicep quite often. I published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-bicep/&#34;&gt;series of articles&lt;/a&gt; on this blog around Bicep. However, there is always more. This series gave me an idea about a complete book on Bicep. And, today, I am announcing this new book project - &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/azurebicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep - Zero to Hero&lt;/a&gt;. This book is still a work in progress and 30% complete. I will be spending a few more weekends completing the rest of the chapters. You can read it as I complete and provide your feedback. Since this is a self-published book, all updates to the book will be free forever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
