<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravikanthchaganti.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Changes in Autogen release 0.5.1</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/changes-in-autogen-release-0_5_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/changes-in-autogen-release-0_5_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft released [version 0.5.1 of the AutoGen](&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/autogen/releases/tag/python-v0.5.1&#34;&gt;Release python-v0.5.1 · microsoft/autogen&lt;/a&gt;) stable build last week, and I quickly reviewed the release notes to verify if there were any breaking changes to what I had been writing so far using AutoGen. There is code refactoring to change the structure of base types. This release provides enhanced support for structured output. When working directly with model clients, you can set to a Pydantic model. Here is an example from the release notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Model Context Protocol server for Azure</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-a-model-context-protocol-server-for-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-a-model-context-protocol-server-for-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/anthropic-model-context-protocol/&#34;&gt;earlier article&lt;/a&gt; in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/mcp/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; introduced Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s Model Context Protocol. It presented an example of building a simple MCP server for use with the Claude desktop application. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rchaganti/mcp-servers/tree/main/hello-world&#34;&gt;hello-world example&lt;/a&gt; was a very basic implementation of an MCP server. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we shall extend our knowledge of creating MCP servers to achieve more practical applications. We will build an MCP server to interact with Microsoft Azure resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anthropic made bootstrap MCP server development easy by providing the &lt;code&gt;create-mcp-server&lt;/code&gt; package. To get started, you need to install this locally as a tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Agents in Microsoft AutoGen framework</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/understanding-agents-in-autogen-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/understanding-agents-in-autogen-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous parts of this series on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/autogen/&#34;&gt;Microsoft AutoGen framework&lt;/a&gt;, we looked at how to get started with the AutoGen framework. We examined the process of building a simple agent using the prebuilt &lt;code&gt;AssistantAgent&lt;/code&gt; in AutoGen and explored the development of a multi-agent team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, what is an agent in the context of AutoGen? How do agents communicate with each other? I needed answers to these questions before proceeding to the next step in using AutoGen to build larger, multi-agent applications. So, I started exploring the &lt;code&gt;Core&lt;/code&gt; package upon which the &lt;code&gt;autogen-chat&lt;/code&gt; is built. This article is a result of that exploration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teams of agents in AutoGen</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/teams-of-agents-in-autogen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/teams-of-agents-in-autogen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous article in this series on Microsoft AutoGen, we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-autogen-framework-for-building-ai-agents-and-applications/&#34;&gt;how to get started with Microsoft AutoGen&lt;/a&gt; and create a simple agent. We built a weather agent capable of retrieving real-time weather data. Through this demonstration, we gained an understanding of the basics of implementing an agent using the AutoGen framework. In this article, we will examine the process of building a team of agents or a multi-agent team to achieve a slightly more complex goal. We will start this exploration by building a single-agent team. Yes, you read that correctly. AutoGen allows you to create a single-agent team. This is useful in running an agent in a loop until a goal is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with AutoGen framework for building AI agents and applications</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-autogen-framework-for-building-ai-agents-and-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-autogen-framework-for-building-ai-agents-and-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been closely following developments in the Agentic AI space. &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoft.github.io/autogen&#34;&gt;AutoGen&lt;/a&gt; from Microsoft Research is emerging as a powerful yet easy-to-use framework for building AI agents and applications. With their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/blog/autogen-v0-4-reimagining-the-foundation-of-agentic-ai-for-scale-extensibility-and-robustness/&#34;&gt;re-architected release&lt;/a&gt; (0.4.0), they have re-imagined building advanced AI applications. This release introduces an asynchronous, event-driven architecture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/ai/autogen-arch.jpg&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/ai/autogen-arch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/glightbox@3.3.0/dist/css/glightbox.min.css&#34;&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &#xA; &lt;script src=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/glightbox@3.3.0/dist/js/glightbox.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &#xA; &lt;script&gt;&#xA;   document.addEventListener(&#39;DOMContentLoaded&#39;, function() {&#xA;     const lightbox = GLightbox({&#xA;       selector: &#39;.glightbox&#39;,&#xA;       touchNavigation: true,&#xA;       loop: true,&#xA;       autoplayVideos: true,&#xA;       zoomable: true,&#xA;       draggable: true,&#xA;       closeButton: true,&#xA;       moreLength: 0&#xA;     });&#xA;   });&#xA; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicted outputs in Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/predicted-outputs-azure-openai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/predicted-outputs-azure-openai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you may want the LLM to perform only minimal changes to what is provided as a prompt. For example, you have a couple of paragraphs of text that you want the LLM to modify to ensure no spelling mistakes. You do not want the LLM to change the overall content, but make sure the misspellings are corrected. This usually helps in reducing the LLM response latency. This is useful in scenarios where you already know a large portion of the expected response and is well-suited for code completion and error detection scenarios. In this part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-openai/&#34;&gt;series of articles on Azure OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;, we will use predicted outputs with Azure OpenAI to build AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallel tool calling in Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/parallel-tool-calling-azure-openai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/parallel-tool-calling-azure-openai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have learned to perform single- and multi-tool calling with the Azure OpenAI API for chat completions. This part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-openai/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; on Azure OpenAI will describe the parallel tool calling feature and how to implement it. Parallel tool calling allows you to perform multiple calls together. This enables parallel execution, result retrieval, and fewer calls to the LLM. Parallelizing tool calls improves overall performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a previous example on retrieving weather at a given location, we examined how to iterate over the LLM response for tool calls and append it to the conversation history before making the next LLM API call.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structured output in Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/structured-output-azure-openai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/structured-output-azure-openai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-openai/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;, we have examined the basics of Azure Open AI, using the chat completions API, streaming responses, and finally, single and multi-tool calling. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we will examine how to return structured output from the LLM response. We will first examine structured output without function calling and then update the earlier multi-function calling example to output JSON instead of text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Structured outputs tell an LLM to follow the schema represented by the &lt;code&gt;response_format&lt;/code&gt; parameter of a request to the LLM. We can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.pydantic.dev/latest/&#34;&gt;Pydantic&lt;/a&gt; to build the schema.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing multiple tool/function calling when using Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-openai-function-calling-with-multiple-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-openai-function-calling-with-multiple-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-openai-function-calling/&#34;&gt;last article&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-openai/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, we learned about function/tool calling. Based on the prompt, the LLM indicates that we must call the &lt;code&gt;get_weather&lt;/code&gt; tool. The LLM finally returns the answer to our prompt using the tool response. However, let us try to add a few more variables to our prompt. The updated prompt will be &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the weather like in Bengaluru next week?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;$ python .\05_function_calling.py&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;get_current_time called with location: Bengaluru&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;The current temperature in Bengaluru is approximately 28.2°C. However, for next week&amp;#39;s weather prediction, you&amp;#39;d need a forecast service as I currently provide only current weather information.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;LLM uses the &lt;code&gt;get_weather&lt;/code&gt; tool to determine the current weather but fails to determine next week&amp;rsquo;s weather. This is because we have not provided any tool for the LLM to determine what next week means. Determining the meaning of next week requires the knowledge of the current date and time. This article will demonstrate how to add multiple tool-calling capabilities to our program. With the updated script, you can receive the weather information for a specific date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing tool/function calling when using Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-openai-function-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-openai-function-calling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last article of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-openai/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, we learned how to use the chat completion API. Towards the end, we learned that the LLMs have a knowledge cut-off date and no real-time access to information. However, this can be bridged using the tool/function calling feature of Azure OpenAI service. In this article, we shall learn how to implement tool calling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s function calling capability lets you connect your language models to external tools and APIs, enabling them to perform a wider range of tasks and access real-time information. This opens up a world of possibilities, allowing your models to interact with the real world in ways never imagined.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using chat completion API in Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/using-chat-completion-api-azure-openai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/using-chat-completion-api-azure-openai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-openai/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, we have looked at the Azure OpenAI completion API, which generates a response for a given prompt. This is a legacy API, and using the chat completion API is recommended. We can build conversational chatbots and similar applications with the chat completion API. This article will examine how to use the Azure OpenAI chat completion API. In the earlier articles, we used the &lt;code&gt;client.completions.create()&lt;/code&gt; function to generate a response. We need to use the &lt;code&gt;client.chat.completions.create()&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;openai&lt;/code&gt; library to build a conversation with the LLM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streaming model responses when using Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/streaming-completions-azure-openai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/streaming-completions-azure-openai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Responses are streamed to the user interface as they are generated using ChatGPT and similar tools. This eliminates the need for the user to wait until the complete response is generated. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we shall look at streaming LLM-generated responses when using Azure OpenAI API in Python.  In the earlier part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-openai/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, we learned about the &lt;code&gt;client.completions.create()&lt;/code&gt; function used to send a prompt to the LLM and retrieve one or more responses. This function supports a parameter called &lt;code&gt;stream&lt;/code&gt; when set to &lt;code&gt;True&lt;/code&gt;, asks LLM to stream the response as it gets generated. The way to handle this response is a bit different from a standard completion response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Azure OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-azure-openai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-azure-openai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generative AI and &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/&#34;&gt;OpenAI&lt;/a&gt; should not be alien anymore. Several startups are already riding this new wave and creating stunning applications that solve several important use cases. I use GenAI regularly to learn and become more efficient in coding. GitHub Copilot has been a good friend. I experimented with creating Large Language Model (LLM) applications using different providers (&lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/docs/overview&#34;&gt;OpenAI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.google.dev/&#34;&gt;Google Gemini&lt;/a&gt;) and in different programming languages. OpenAI provides client libraries that can be used with any provider that offers an OpenAI-compatible API. For example, we can use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/openai/&#34;&gt;OpenAI Python library&lt;/a&gt; to work with OpenAI and Azure OpenAI services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Bicep to provision Azure Red Hat OpenShift cluster</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/using-bicep-to-provision-azure-red-hat-openshift-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/using-bicep-to-provision-azure-red-hat-openshift-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Azure Red Hat OpenShift (ARO) service provides fully managed and highly available OpenShift clusters on Azure jointly operated by Microsoft and Red Hat. There are different ways to provision an ARO cluster.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Azure Portal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Azure CLI or Azure PowerShell&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Azure Resource Manager (ARM) / Bicep templates&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management (RHACM)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article will explore using Bicep language to provision an ARO cluster.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Examples in this article use Azure CLI for interacting with Azure resources and deployments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK for Go - Authentication methods - Chained Credentials</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-sdk-for-go-authentication-methods-chained-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-sdk-for-go-authentication-methods-chained-credentials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-go/&#34;&gt;in this series&lt;/a&gt;, you learned how to use different types of credentials that the Azure SDK for Go offers. You used specific credential types to authenticate with Azure in all the examples. You use a set of credential types for the development environment and a different set for production use cases. However, what if you want to use the code unmodified between development and production? What if you must test the code that uses managed identity credentials locally where the type of credentials you must use are different? This is where credential chaining comes to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK for Go - Authentication methods - Managed Identity Credential</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-sdk-for-go-authentication-methods-managed-identity-credential/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-sdk-for-go-authentication-methods-managed-identity-credential/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you have applications or services that run in the Azure cloud infrastructure and require access to Azure services, the best way to authenticate to Azure is to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/active-directory/managed-identities-azure-resources/overview&#34;&gt;managed identity&lt;/a&gt;. Using managed identity, you can eliminate the need to manage artifacts such as secrets, certificates, and credentials. For example, if you need to access Azure Key Vault to retrieve an API key for authentication purposes. To do this, you must first authenticate to the Key Vault service. With managed identity, you get automatically authenticated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK for Go - Authentication methods - Environmental credential</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-sdk-for-go-authentication-methods-environmental-credential/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-sdk-for-go-authentication-methods-environmental-credential/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last part of this series, you learned how to use different credential types in a local development environment. Another method you can use within local development and in a hosted/deployed service is providing credentials through environment variables. This is done using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pkg.go.dev/github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-go/sdk/azidentity#NewEnvironmentCredential&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NewEnvironmentCredential()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; method in the &lt;code&gt;azidentity&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;// github.com/rchaganti/azure-go/02-auth101/envCredential.go&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;cred&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;azidentity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;NewEnvironmentCredential&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;Fatal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This credential type supports multiple types of authentication in the following order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK for Go - Authentication methods for local development environment</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-sdk-for-go-authentication-methods-for-local-dev-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-sdk-for-go-authentication-methods-for-local-dev-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2023-07-13-getting-started-with-azure-sdk-for-go&#34;&gt;earlier article introduced&lt;/a&gt; you to the Azure SDK for Go. In the example towards the end of that article, you may have noticed how the &lt;code&gt;NewAzureCLICredential&lt;/code&gt; method of the &lt;code&gt;azidentity&lt;/code&gt; package was used to access locally available Azure CLI credentials. This is perfect for local development and is not recommended for production environments. The Azure SDK supports different types of credentials depending on where your Go code is running. In this article in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-go/&#34;&gt;Azure SDK for Go series&lt;/a&gt;, you will learn about each of these credential types and when you use each of these credentials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Azure SDK for Go</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2023-07-13-getting-started-with-azure-sdk-for-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2023-07-13-getting-started-with-azure-sdk-for-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Azure provides vast services from basic computing to AI/ML. Azure Resource Manager (ARM) is our entry point to access and manage these services and provides a consistent management layer (APIs) that enables you to work with resources in Azure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/arm-arch.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/arm-arch.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/glightbox@3.3.0/dist/css/glightbox.min.css&#34;&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &#xA; &lt;script src=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/glightbox@3.3.0/dist/js/glightbox.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &#xA; &lt;script&gt;&#xA;   document.addEventListener(&#39;DOMContentLoaded&#39;, function() {&#xA;     const lightbox = GLightbox({&#xA;       selector: &#39;.glightbox&#39;,&#xA;       touchNavigation: true,&#xA;       loop: true,&#xA;       autoplayVideos: true,&#xA;       zoomable: true,&#xA;       draggable: true,&#xA;       closeButton: true,&#xA;       moreLength: 0&#xA;     });&#xA;   });&#xA; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully automated Kubernetes cluster deployment on Azure in under 8 minutes</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-26-fully-automated-kubernetes-cluster-deployment-on-azure-in-under-8-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-26-fully-automated-kubernetes-cluster-deployment-on-azure-in-under-8-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier article, I wrote about provisioning a virtual Kubernetes cluster with kubeadm](&lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-13-installing-and-configuring-kubernetes-cluster-using-kubeadm-on-ubuntu/)&#34;&gt;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-13-installing-and-configuring-kubernetes-cluster-using-kubeadm-on-ubuntu/)&lt;/a&gt;. I use this method on a laptop with limited resources. This is good to a large extent but not good enough when I want to scale my experiments and learning. This is where I began planning my Kubernetes lab on Azure. I needed something I could spin quickly with no manual intervention. Given my interest in the Bicep language, I naturally wrote a Bicep template to perform this deployment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully Automated Kubernetes Cluster Deployment on Azure in Under 8 Minutes</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/fully-automated-kubernetes-cluster-deployment-on-azure-in-under-8-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/fully-automated-kubernetes-cluster-deployment-on-azure-in-under-8-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier article, I had written about &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/posts/installing-and-configuring-kubernetes-cluster-using-kubeadm-on-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;provisioning a virtual Kubernetes cluster using kubeadm&lt;/a&gt;. I use this method on a laptop with limited resources. This is good to a large extent but not good enough when I want to scale my experiments and learning. This is where I started looking at creating my Kubernetes lab on Azure. I needed something that could spin fast and without manual intervention. Given my interest in the Bicep language, I wrote a Bicep template to perform this deployment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and using Azure Container Instances service - Multi-container Applications using Bicep</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-03-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-multi-container-apps-using-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-03-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-multi-container-apps-using-bicep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous article, we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/&#34;&gt;getting started with Azure Container Instances service&lt;/a&gt;, learned some basic concepts of ACI, and saw an example of provisioning a hello-world application. In this article, we shall extend this knowledge by provisioning a multi-container application to ACI using Bicep templates. You can also use a YAML method of provisioning multi-container applications to ACI. We shall look at this later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we learned earlier, a container group resembles a Kubernetes pod. The containers within the group share resources such as network and storage. The resource usage of containers can be controlled at the container group level. As a general rule of thumb, we should group containers with similar lifecycle and resource requirements into a container group. The multi-container groups are available for Linux containers only at the moment. Based on the region, there will be additional restrictions in terms of resource allocation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and using Azure Container Instances service - The Basics</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-02-understanding-and-using-azure-container-instances-service-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier article, we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-01-containerization-in-azure&#34;&gt;different containerization options&lt;/a&gt; in Microsoft Azure. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we shall start with Azure Container Instances (ACI) and learn the fundamentals. In a later article, we will learn how to perform multi-container applications to ACI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;azure-container-instances&#34;&gt;Azure Container Instances&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Container Instances (ACI) service offers a quick and easy way to run containers in the Microsoft Azure cloud. It is as simple as running a container locally using the Docker engine. ACI does not provide full container orchestration. ACI is great for applications that require faster startup times and hassle-free management. ACI runs inside Azure VMs and therefore provides isolation enabled by virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containerization in Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-01-containerization-in-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-11-01-containerization-in-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Containerization is everywhere &amp;ndash; from on-premises data centers to the edge and in the cloud. We have been using containers right from development to production. I wrote about VS Code development containers and how &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/bicep-feature-in-vscode-devcontainer/&#34;&gt;I have standardized my development environment using devcontainers.&lt;/a&gt; There are several options for companies to run containerized applications in production. we can run individual application containers on a container host using engines like Docker. We can use tools like Docker &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/compose/&#34;&gt;Compose&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/swarm/&#34;&gt;Swarm&lt;/a&gt; for slightly complex multi-container, multi-host environments. However, it becomes complex to manage such environments. This needs us to implement a physical or virtualized server environment and handle all operational overhead associated with running our data center.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Book] Azure Bicep - Zero to Hero is complete</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-07-09-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero-s-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-07-09-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero-s-complete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally! I published the final chapter in my book &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/azurebicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep - Zero to Hero&lt;/a&gt; today. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/book-announcing-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero/&#34;&gt;started this project more than a year ago&lt;/a&gt; with an intention that I will complete it before end of year 2021. However, a few personal life events made me shift focus to my family and that pushed the book timelines to the right. In the last few weeks, I spent good amount of my personal time to explore a few new areas within Bicep and formed the content for the last few chapters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local CI/CD for your Bicep templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-07-09-local-ci-cd-for-your-bicep-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/2022-07-09-local-ci-cd-for-your-bicep-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the very important aspects of Infrastructure as Code (IaC) is automation. And, it is not just about the configuration tasks that we must automate but it is also the entire validation and deployment / delivery workflow itself. We call this a continuous integration (CI) and continuous delivery / deployment (CD) pipeline. The core idea of a CI/CD pipeline is to accelerate testing and uncover any bugs and fix those bugs before the code reaches production. There are many ways and tools to implement a CI/CD pipeline. We can use GitHub actions or Jenkins or AppVeyor to name just a few. But, as a starting point, I prefer building a local CI/CD pipeline using git hooks. In this article, I will show you how I built a simple test and deploy pipeline for my Azure Bicep experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working with Azure Bicep Public modules registry</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/working-with-azure-bicep-public-modules-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/working-with-azure-bicep-public-modules-registry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting with Bicep version 0.5.6, Microsoft added support for consuming from a public module&#xA;repository hosted on Microsoft Container Registry (MCR). To consume a module from Microsoft’s&#xA;pubic registry, you need to use the following syntax.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;module &amp;lt;module-id&amp;gt; &amp;#39;br/public:&amp;lt;module-group&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;module-name&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&amp;#39; = { ... }&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;br/public&lt;/code&gt; indicates that you want to consume the module hosted on MCR. Here is an example of&#xA;creating a Azure virtual network using the virtual-network module. The version tag is mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Bicep as a feature in VS Code development containers</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-feature-in-vscode-devcontainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-feature-in-vscode-devcontainer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio Code &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/remote/containers&#34;&gt;development containers&lt;/a&gt; are magic! With the help of VS Code Remote - Containers extension and Docker Desktop, you can run a full-featured development environment within a container.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/assets/docs/devcontainers/containers/architecture-containers.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/assets/docs/devcontainers/containers/architecture-containers.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/glightbox@3.3.0/dist/css/glightbox.min.css&#34;&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &#xA; &lt;script src=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/glightbox@3.3.0/dist/js/glightbox.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA; &#xA; &#xA; &lt;script&gt;&#xA;   document.addEventListener(&#39;DOMContentLoaded&#39;, function() {&#xA;     const lightbox = GLightbox({&#xA;       selector: &#39;.glightbox&#39;,&#xA;       touchNavigation: true,&#xA;       loop: true,&#xA;       autoplayVideos: true,&#xA;       zoomable: true,&#xA;       draggable: true,&#xA;       closeButton: true,&#xA;       moreLength: 0&#xA;     });&#xA;   });&#xA; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Guest Configuration - Assignments</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-assignments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-introduction/&#34;&gt;last part of this series&lt;/a&gt; around &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-policy-guest-configuration/&#34;&gt;Azure Policy Guest Configuration&lt;/a&gt;, you got an introduction to what is Guest Configuration. In this part, you will learn about assigning Guest Configuration policies and initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Policy Guest Configuration (GC) is an extension to Azure Policy and therefore use the same JSON definition structure. For example, here is the (redacted) GC definition for the policy &lt;em&gt;Audit Windows machines that do not have the specified Windows PowerShell execution policy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Book] - Annoucing Azure Bicep - Zero to Hero</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/book-announcing-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/book-announcing-azure-bicep-zero-to-hero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many are struggling to make ends meet ever since the pandemic started. Therefore, I decided that all proceeds from this book will go to charity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Project Bicep&lt;/a&gt; is undoubtedly the best thing that happened in the Azure world, and I have been following the development and using Bicep quite often. I published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-bicep/&#34;&gt;series of articles&lt;/a&gt; on this blog around Bicep. However, there is always more. This series gave me an idea about a complete book on Bicep. And, today, I am announcing this new book project - &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/azurebicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep - Zero to Hero&lt;/a&gt;. This book is still a work in progress and 30% complete. I will be spending a few more weekends completing the rest of the chapters. You can read it as I complete and provide your feedback. Since this is a self-published book, all updates to the book will be free forever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep v0.4 and the linter</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-v0-4-and-linter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-v0-4-and-linter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bicep v0.4.1 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/bicep/releases/tag/v0.4.1&#34;&gt;was released yesterday&lt;/a&gt;. This release includes a bunch of bug fixes, more snippets, and most importantly, a linter!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lint_(software)&#34;&gt;Linters&lt;/a&gt; bring in a variety of capabilities to a developer toolkit. These tools can help you perform static code analysis, check compliance against a style guide, find syntax errors, and flag potential optimizations in the code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a developer, linting support in an IDE is a must. With this Bicep release, Microsoft added support for linting of Bicep files in VS Code and at the command line. To realize the benefits of linting, you must upgrade Bicep CLI and the VS Code extension to v4.0.1 or later. The current set of linter rules are minimal and taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/test-cases&#34;&gt;arm-ttk test cases&lt;/a&gt;. Both VS Code extension and Bicep CLI check for all available rules by default and all rules are set at warning level. Based on the level of a rule, you will see errors or warnings or informational messages within the editor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Container Image</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-container-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-container-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/_/microsoft-azure-cli&#34;&gt;Azure CLI container image&lt;/a&gt; for one of my side projects, I started looking for an image that contains Bicep CLI as well. I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/miqm&#34;&gt;Mikolaj Mackowiak&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/miqm/bicep-cli&#34;&gt;Bicep-cli image&lt;/a&gt;. This was what I really needed and it includes both Azure CLI and Bicep CLI. However, just as a fun side project, I wanted to publish my own image as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Visualizer</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-visualizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-visualizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-bicep/&#34;&gt;a series of articles&lt;/a&gt; to introduce Bicep language fundamentals. I really enjoyed working on these articles and learnt quite a lot in that process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Bicep team &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/bicep/releases/tag/v0.3.539&#34;&gt;released version 0.3.539&lt;/a&gt; of Bicep command line as well as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-azuretools.vscode-bicep&#34;&gt;VS Code extension&lt;/a&gt; a few hours ago and it came with a lot of goodness &amp;ndash; bug fixes as well as new shiny things! One of the first things that caught my eye was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/bicep/pull/2357&#34;&gt;Bicep visualizer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Language - Beyond Basics - Scoped Deployment</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-scoped-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-scoped-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When using ARM JSON templates, you can deploy to any of the four supported scopes &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/deploy-to-management-group?tabs=azure-cli&#34;&gt;management groups&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/deploy-to-tenant?tabs=azure-cli&#34;&gt;tenants&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/deploy-to-subscription?tabs=azure-cli&#34;&gt;subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/deploy-to-resource-group?tabs=azure-cli&#34;&gt;resource groups&lt;/a&gt;. What you can deploy using ARM JSON templates differs between these different target scopes. For example, you can create resource groups at the subscription level only. You identify the target scope for an ARM JSON template using the &lt;code&gt;$schema&lt;/code&gt; element in the template. Each scope has a specific schema.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Language - Beyond Basics - Conditional Deployment</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-conditional-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-conditional-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you go to the Azure portal and deploy a service, you may have seen a prompt where you are asked to select an existing resource group or create a new resource group. And, a few more service deployment scenarios might ask you to select between selecting an existing or creating a new storage account.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/biceprg.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/biceprg.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Language - Beyond Basics - Modules</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-modules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reusability and repeatability are two basics requirements when you want to implement Infrastructure as Code (IaC) practices. You looked at how parameters can be added to Bicep files to make those programs reusable. This is the first step towards modularizing your programs. With the ARM JSON templates, you might have used linked templates that are meant to provide similar functionality. Bicep has support for modularity and helps simplify complex configurations into smaller reusable modules.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides and Demo Scripts: Global Azure Bootcamp 2021 - Azure Bicep</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-and-demo-scripts-introduction-to-azure-bicep-gab-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-and-demo-scripts-introduction-to-azure-bicep-gab-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I had the opportunity to present live (virtually) at the Global Azure Bootcamp 2021. My session was around &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt;. I really enjoyed preparing for and delivering this session.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you follow me on Twitter or this blog, you know I&amp;rsquo;ve started a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/series/azure-bicep&#34;&gt;new series of articles on Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt;. These articles are essentially notes from my Bicep learning sessions. There are a few more pending in the next few days, but overall, I really enjoyed learning about Bicep. This series and my session at GAB 2021 helped me share my learning with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Language - Beyond Basics - Output</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-output/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You use outputs in ARM JSON templates to return value(s) from the deployment. Returning output from a template is not mandatory, but it is useful in scenarios such as deploying templates through a CI/CD pipeline or creating templates as reusable modules. To support this, Bicep language has an &lt;code&gt;outputs&lt;/code&gt; element.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;output&#34;&gt;Output&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syntax for adding an &lt;code&gt;output&lt;/code&gt; element to Bicep is:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Language - Beyond Basics - Iterations</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-iterations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-iterations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When working ARM templates, you may have come across a situation where you want to provision multiple instances of a resource with similar configuration. For example, multiple storage accounts or virtual machines or multiple data disks attached to a virtual machine. In the JSON template language, the &lt;code&gt;copy&lt;/code&gt; element is used for this purpose. Bicep language has a few different ways you can achieve this at different levels like resources, resource properties, and outputs. Variable iterations &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/bicep/issues/1814&#34;&gt;are not available yet&lt;/a&gt; and mostly coming as a part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/bicep/projects/7#card-56641753&#34;&gt;0.4 release&lt;/a&gt; which is due by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/bicep/milestone/7&#34;&gt;May 25th 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Language - Beyond Basics - Expressions</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-expressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Expressions are a critical part of any programming language. For a Domain-Specific Language (DSL) such as Bicep that transpiles to ARM template JSON, expressions add a great value in reducing the complexity in authoring templates. All built-in functions available within ARM JSON template language are available within Bicep as well. Using these functions and the supported language constructs, you can create some powerful expressions in Bicep that significantly reduces the complexity compared to JSON templates. In this article, you will learn about writing a few different ways of writing expressions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Language - Beyond Basics - Variables</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-variables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This part of the series will take you beyond Bicep language basics by showing you how to add variables to your Bicep files. If you have worked on ARM JSON templates, you know that variables exist there as well. The primary intention of using variables in either ARM JSON templates or Bicep language is to bring in a balance between &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/#free-form-vs-known-configuration&#34;&gt;free-form vs fixed configurations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Language - Beyond Basics - Parameters</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/bicep-basics-beyond-basics-parameters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous part, you learned how you can get started with Bicep language to write your first Bicep file. As you learned, &lt;code&gt;resource&lt;/code&gt; keyword along with resource declaration and resource properties are the minimum required in a Bicep file. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, you will see what is beyond those basics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;parameters&#34;&gt;Parameters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the goals of Infrastructure as Code (IaC) practice is to create reusable and repeatable automation for deploying your infrastructure. To make this happen, you need to parameterize your infrastructure configuration definitions. In this case, your Bicep files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Azure Bicep</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-azure-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-azure-bicep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/series/azure-bicep&#34;&gt;new series of articles on Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt;, you learnt about what is Azure Bicep and why it is needed. In this part, you will learn about how to get started with Azure Bicep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-bicep&#34;&gt;Installing Bicep&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start working with Bicep you will need, at a minimum, the Bicep CLI. There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/bicep-install?tabs=azure-powershell#install-bicep-cli&#34;&gt;multiple ways to get Bicep CLI&lt;/a&gt; on to your system. On Windows systems, you can use any of the following methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Bicep</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/introduction-to-azure-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/introduction-to-azure-bicep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I started preparing slides and demos for &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/speaking-at-global-azure-bootcamp-india-2021&#34;&gt;my session on Azure Bicep at the Global Azure Bootcamp 2021&lt;/a&gt;, I made a bunch of notes. As a part of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/series/azure-bicep&#34;&gt;new series of articles on Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt;, I will start sharing those notes here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt; is a new Domain-Specific Language (DSL) for declaratively deploying Azure resources. Bicep is not a general purpose programming language but a transparent abstraction for Azure Resource Manager (ARM) Templates. This ensures that the properties that are valid in ARM templates are valid in Bicep as well. Azure Bicep acts as a transpiler for generating ARM templates from Bicep files. But, what is wrong with ARM templates?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieve and save Project Bicep examples from GitHub</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/retrieve-and-save-project-bicep-examples-from-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/retrieve-and-save-project-bicep-examples-from-github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Project Bicep&lt;/a&gt; aims to simplify how you author Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates. Bicep is a new declarative language and a transpiler. This transparent abstraction takes a bicep file and transpiles it into an ARM template JSON. The Bicep CLI provides the necessary capablities to compile bicep files to ARM templates and decompile ARM templates into bicep files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bicep language itself is very easy to understand and start using. However, as you start learning it may be helpful to see a few examples and draw some inspiration as you build your won bicep files. Project Bicep respository on GitHub has a good number of examples for varied level of complexity. While looking at these, I thought it may be a good idea to create scripts that can retrieve and save selected example locally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Global Azure Bootcamp India 2021</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/speaking-at-global-azure-bootcamp-india-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/speaking-at-global-azure-bootcamp-india-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/bicep.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://globalazure.net/&#34;&gt;Global Azure Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; is happening this year from April 15th to 17th as an online event. And, I will be speaking this year. I submitted a couple of sessions and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/bicep&#34;&gt;Azure Bicep&lt;/a&gt; session got accepted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-is-azure-bicep&#34;&gt;So, what is Azure Bicep?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Bicep is the Domain-Specific Language (DSL) and a transparent abstraction built on top of Azure Resource Manager (ARM). The intention behind this project is to simplify authoring ARM templates. Bicep language transpiles into an ARM template JSON which you can deploy using already well-known methods and your existing CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Guest Configuration - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-policy-guest-configuration-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As your Azure adoption increases and as you on-board various departments and groups within your organization to start using Azure services, it is important that you put in place some level of governance. As cloud architect, you would want control over who can create what type resources, where can they create those resources and how many. You would also want to standardize on the deployments so that the configuration of resources is in compliance with your organization standards. Among many other aspects like this you would want the ability to track your cloud cost more granularly for every service deployed in the cloud and for every business unit or group within your organization. To address this and to implement efficient governance Azure offers features and services such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/policy/overview&#34;&gt;Policies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/management-groups/&#34;&gt;Management Groups&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/features/resource-graph/&#34;&gt;Resource Graph&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/blueprints/overview&#34;&gt;Blueprints&lt;/a&gt;. Here is an excellent depiction of Azure governance architecture from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/us-partner-blog/2019/07/24/azure-governance/&#34;&gt;partner blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Community Conference - 2020</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-community-conference-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-community-conference-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 660; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/azconf.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.azconf.dev/&#34;&gt;Azure Community Conference&lt;/a&gt; is a 3 day multi-track virtual event scheduled to go live on November 24th 2020. This event is being organized by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Microsoft-Azure-Bangalore/&#34;&gt;Bangalore Azure User Group&lt;/a&gt;. The target audience of this virtual event are cloud and web developers working with open source and cloud native technologies on the Microsoft stack. This event will be a free two conference days that includes a free workshop as well. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.azconf.dev/#tickets&#34;&gt;Registration for this event&lt;/a&gt; is open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using secrets in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-secrets-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-secrets-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this series so far, you have seen how to get started with ARM templates, parameterize them by adding parameters, and optimize them using variables, expressions, and user-defined functions. It is now time to move on to more advanced topics and begin building the template for the remaining components of the architecture shown above. In the architecture shown above, you will implement an ARM template that provisions virtual machines, requiring the administrator and domain-join credentials as inputs. Also, the configuration scripts used to configure the guest OS may need to access an internal storage account blob, which requires the storage connection strings and access keys. Storing these secrets in plain text is not recommended. Also, as an architect, you may want to standardize on passwords for local administrator accounts and avoid sharing domain-join credentials with any user when provisioning an ARM template. This needs a more centralized credential and secret store. Azure Vault provides this capability. Today, you will learn how to handle secrets such as passwords, access keys, certificates, and more in an ARM template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using functions in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-functions-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-using-functions-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/&#34;&gt;Expressions in ARM template language&lt;/a&gt; are a way to reduce complexity in the templates. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/&#34;&gt;Using parameters and variables in ARM templates&lt;/a&gt; always requires the use of expressions. Parameter and variable values are combined with standard (built-in) template functions (STF) to create complex expressions to implement the business requirements and implement known configurations. Updated ARM template syntax introduced the ability to implement user-defined functions for complicated expressions and use repeatedly in your templates. In this part, you will learn more about standard template functions and learn how to implement user-defined functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Using expressions and variables in ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days-using-expressions-and-variables-in-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, you learned how to use VS Code and ARM Tools extension to get started with the ARM template development, how to perform a subscription scoped deployment to create a resource group and then looked at resource group scoped deployment to create a storage account and a virtual network resources. You learned about parameterizing the ARM template so that it becomes reusable. Equipped with that knowledge, you can now start digging into expressions and variables in the ARM templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Adding parameters to ARM templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-adding-parameters-to-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 760; margin: 1.5rem auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armin30/templatearchitecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, you learned the template syntax and authored an ARM template that provisions the resource group needed for the above architecture. This deployment was performed at the subscription level using Azure CLI. In this part, you will create another template for performing additional resource &amp;ndash; storage account and virtual network &amp;ndash; provisioning at the resource group level. You will, then, parameterize this template to understand how to add parameters to ARM templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - ARM template basics</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-arm-template-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last two parts of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/azure-resource-manager-in-30-days/&#34;&gt;the series&lt;/a&gt;, you have seen a brief introduction to Azure Resource Manager and the services that complement ARM to extend its functionality or support the services offered by ARM. You also looked at an overview of ARM templates and the tools available to design, author, and deploy these templates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting this part of the series for the next few days, you will start learning about authoring ARM templates right from the basics and to the advanced template syntax and techniques with a goal to build an ARM template that helps provision the following architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Tools for ARM template design, authoring, and deployment</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-tools-for-arm-template-design-authoring-and-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-tools-for-arm-template-design-authoring-and-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of this series of articles on Azure Resource Manager (ARM) provided a quick overview of ARM. You looked a quick introduction to ARM templates as well and looked at an overview of different template deployment methods. In this part of the series, we will look at different methods to author ARM templates and an in-depth look at preferred deployment methods. You can choose any of the methods mentioned here but this series of articles will use one preferred method each for authoring and deploying templates. You will read more about those methods and the reasons behind that choice as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Manager - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/azure-resource-manager-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I had written a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/arm-templates/&#34;&gt;series of articles&lt;/a&gt; introducing and diving deep into authoring Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates. A few things have changed in authoring ARM templates and new features got added in the recent past. I thought it is probably a better time to revisit and do it all over again. At the same time, I thought why just limit to just authoring ARM templates. Over the years, I made notes around ARM and learned quite a bit. Starting today, I will share those notes with you here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Global Azure Bootcamp - Azure CLI 2.0</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-and-demo-scripts-from-azure-cli-2-0-tips-and-tricks-session-at-globalazurebootcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-and-demo-scripts-from-azure-cli-2-0-tips-and-tricks-session-at-globalazurebootcamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity over the weekend to speak at the Global Azure Bootcamp organized by local Microsoft user groups. This event was held at ABB office in Bangalore and I must say that they have done a splendid job. It was a very well organized event. I had only one session and it was about Azure CLI 2.0 Tips and Tricks. I mentioned earlier that I am using CLI mostly these days to work with Azure resources and in this session I shared some tips and tricks around making it easier to work with Azure resource management using Azure CLI 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Experts Live India – Azure at the command line</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/session-slides-experts-live-india-azure-at-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/session-slides-experts-live-india-azure-at-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to speak at the inaugural edition of Experts Live India 2019 over the weekend. It was a great experience. The organizers did a great job even when there were teething facilities issues that plagued the event right from the start.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first session was on Azure at the command line. In this session, I walked through both Az CLI 2.0 and Az PowerShell modules and explained the differences to help the audience choose the right tool for their job. The slides do not contain a huge deal of information as I preferred showing the audience a good demo to understand the differences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Azure MVP Bootcamp – Microsoft Azure Cloud and DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-from-azure-mvp-bootcamp-microsoft-azure-cloud-and-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-from-azure-mvp-bootcamp-microsoft-azure-cloud-and-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege to join the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miraclesoft.com/&#34;&gt;Miracle &lt;/a&gt;team at Visakhapatnam today for an Azure MVP bootcamp. I spoke about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rchaganti/Presentations/tree/master/Azure-Boot-Camp-Vizag2016&#34;&gt;Microsoft Azure Cloud and DevOps&lt;/a&gt;. This event, I must say, it a very well organized and orchestrated. I have been to conferences and events in India and outside India and never seen this level of care of speakers and attendees anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started my day with a good morning walk along the beach and just loved it. I wish I get to do this often.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Template Deployment Improvements in Azure Portal</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/custom-template-deployment-improvements-in-azure-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/custom-template-deployment-improvements-in-azure-portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When testing ARM templates, I typically use the custom template deployment option in the Azure Portal. This UI option just got better! This deployment option now supports lists the parameters, variables, and resources used in template in a nice treeview navigation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start a new deployment, you can click on New -&amp;gt; Template Deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate11-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate11-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This opens up the Custom Deployment blade. Click on Edit Template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Forcing WMF 4.0 when using DSC Extension</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-forcing-wmf-4-0-when-using-dsc-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-forcing-wmf-4-0-when-using-dsc-extension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This subject won&amp;rsquo;t really need a post of its own but I will do it anyway. In the previous part of this &lt;a href=&#34;http://azrs.tk/armseries&#34;&gt;ARM series&lt;/a&gt;, I showed how we can use the domain join extension instead of DSC to join a VM to an existing AD domain. This resulted is huge savings in time taken to deploy the entire scenario. When I was talking to my good friend, fellow PowerShell MVP and all-things-Azure guru, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bgelens&#34;&gt;Ben Gelens&lt;/a&gt;, he was quick to point that the delays when using DSC extension here could be due to the install of WMF 5.0. Indeed!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Domain Join Extension</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-domain-join-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-domain-join-extension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The scenario that we used to understand and build ARM templates contained a domain controller VM along with one or more VMs that joined the domain service hosted by the DC VM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate9-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate9-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make sure the VMs join the domain, we used PowerShell DSC configuration. One of the biggest quirks, at least what I faced, with DSC extension with ARM templates is that it takes little longer to complete. For example, the complete scenario deployment took almost 48 minutes to deploy. I am not making up that number. Here is the proof.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Putting it all together</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-putting-it-all-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-putting-it-all-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this series so far, we looked at building ARM templates by example. The focus was not really on the resource types or how to use resource definitions. Instead, our focus was on learning the basics of template language. To that extent, we have a scenario that we want to deploy and we are incrementally building the template for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate8-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate8-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While building an ARM template for this, we looked at how to use parameters and variables. We looked at using copy object to create multiple instances of a resource type without really writing the resource definition multiple times. We went on to find out how we can define dependencies between different resource types so they are orchestrated in the right order. We looked at how we can decompose the template into purpose-specific external templates and how to link them together. While learning these concepts, we created a template that almost built the scenario we started with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Linked Templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-linked-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-linked-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the ARM template authoring best practices is to decompose the JSON template, if applicable, into multiple target-specific templates. Think of this as creating re-usable code. You can leverage the re-usable parts of your code within multiple aspects of your application or the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For linking different external templates within the main template, we need to define the &lt;em&gt;Microsoft.Resources/deployments&lt;/em&gt; resource instance. Before we proceed let us look at the scenario for which we are building an ARM template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Defining Resource Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-defining-resource-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-defining-resource-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will continue learning about building ARM templates by looking at how we can define dependencies between resources. To recap, here is the scenario we are working on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate6-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate6-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the earlier parts of this series, we created the storage account, virtual network, a public IP, a load balancer, and added all inbound NAT rules required for the virtual machine RDP access. If you notice, we have components that depend on others. For example, the inbound NAT rules depend on the load balancer. Similarly, VMs depend on network interfaces which in turn depend on the virtual network. In the absence of dependencies, ARM will attempt to deploy these resources in parallel which may result in errors. So, within the resource template, we need to define these dependencies so that ARM can make decisions about the deployment sequence. There are multiple ways of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Copy Object</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-copy-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-copy-object/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are following this series, by now you know how to use parameters and variables in ARM template language. We used that knowledge to create a template that creates relevant things to like storage account and virtual network. Let us revisit the scenario.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate5-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate5-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part, we will extend the template to add publicIP, load balancer, and RDP endpoints for the virtual machines. Before we do that, let us review what we need. To achieve what we want in this, we will use copy object in the template.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Variables</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-variables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following this series on &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/series/arm-templates/&#34;&gt;ARM templates&lt;/a&gt;, in the last part, we started with a sample scenario that we are using to build an ARM template. Here it is again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate4-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate4-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-parameters/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt;, we completed creation of storage account required for backing the OS and data disks for virtual machines in the deployment. The next step in our scenario is to create the virtual network for the VM connectivity. A virtual network and any subnets required must exist before the creation of virtual machines. So, in today’s article, we will see how we can use variables in the ARM template language while incrementally building an ARM template for our scenario and add virtual network. Towards the end, we will review some best practices guidance with regards to using parameters and variables in developing ARM templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – Using Parameters</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-using-parameters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the earlier parts of this &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/series/arm-templates/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;, we briefly looked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-an-introduction/&#34;&gt;different methods of deploying ARM templates&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-the-basics/&#34;&gt;basics of ARM template language&lt;/a&gt;. Starting today’s article, we will see our leaning in action. To get going with our leaning, we will start building the ARM template for the following scenario.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate3-1.png&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/armtemplate3-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will incrementally build this scenario by learning different aspects of ARM template language. We won’t be covering all resource types in Azure but we will cover every aspect of the ARM template language and functions and expressions used in the template language. We will also review best practices in building these ARM templates as we proceed forward in this series.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Future Unleashed – Authoring ARM Templates</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-from-future-unleashed-2015-authoring-azure-resource-manager-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-from-future-unleashed-2015-authoring-azure-resource-manager-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;figure &#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/futureunleashed.jpg&#34; class=&#34;glightbox&#34; data-gallery=&#34;post-images&#34; data-glightbox=&#34;description: &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ravikanthchaganti.com/images/futureunleashed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 0.5rem; box-shadow: 0 4px 6px -1px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a great time at Future Unleashed 2015 talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://139.59.40.198/blog/authoring-azure-resource-manager-templates-microsoft-future-unleashed-2015-futureunleased/&#34;&gt;Authoring Azure Resource Manager Templates. &lt;/a&gt;This was a one-day technical event where there were 11 tracks covering different aspects from Cloud to Data to Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The breakout session setup was a little weird. There were no walls for the breakout session room (or whatever you call it). It was just a big expo hall with 11 tracks spread across like exhibitor booths. All the attendees had to wear a headset to hear the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – The Basics</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a part of this series, we will go through the language semantics of writing ARM templates. We will explore each and every aspect of the ARM template language and go through multiple examples to understand the concepts better. We won’t focus much on the resource types and resource definitions until we complete the discussion around the language semantics and artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us get started.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;tools-for-the-job&#34;&gt;Tools for the job&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JSON templates for ARM can be edited in notepad too. But, there are better tools that can help us with this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Azure Resource Manager Templates – An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/building-azure-resource-manager-templates-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-in/documentation/articles/resource-group-overview/&#34;&gt;Azure Resource Manager&lt;/a&gt; isn’t a new thing! It was announced during &lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2014/DEV-B224&#34;&gt;Build 2014&lt;/a&gt;. ARM is certainly the preferred way, with more and more services getting ARM support, to deploy Azure services. Microsoft also announced that the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fuAmcfmo3X0&#34;&gt;Azure Stack release&lt;/a&gt; will feature Azure Resource Manager and the template deployment. This means that learning how to use ARM and write you own templates is an essential skill not just for public cloud but also for the private and hybrid cloud administrators.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Reboot Camp Bangalore - Cloud Computing for IT Professionals</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-from-reboot-camp-bangalore-keynote-cloud-computing-for-it-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/slides-from-reboot-camp-bangalore-keynote-cloud-computing-for-it-professionals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to do the keynote at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rebootblr.azurewebsites.net/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Reboot Camp Bangalore&lt;/a&gt;. This is a community driven event with support from Microsoft. The theme for the event was cloud computing and Microsoft Cloud offerings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my keynote, I talked about what cloud computing means to the IT professionals and how they should get ready for the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the slides from my keynote.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;slideshare-embed&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;iframe&#xA;      src=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/w4XP9qWqOyvpZP&#34;&#xA;      style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: 1px solid #ccc; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&#xA;      frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      marginheight=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&#xA;      allowfullscreen&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Community Day 2014 – Introduction to Microsoft Azure Compute</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/session-slides-community-day-2014-introduction-to-microsoft-azure-compute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/session-slides-community-day-2014-introduction-to-microsoft-azure-compute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Azure offers several services each categorized into one of the four major categories – Compute, Data, App, and Network Services. This session takes you through an overview of the Microsoft Azure Compute Services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;slideshare-embed&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;iframe&#xA;      src=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/62eQ9o9FToFmEq&#34;&#xA;      style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: 1px solid #ccc; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&#xA;      frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      marginheight=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&#xA;      allowfullscreen&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 5px;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a title=&#34;Introduction to Microsoft Azure Compute&#34; href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/kanthrc/introduction-to-microsoft-azure-compute&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Introduction to Microsoft Azure Compute&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/kanthrc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ravikanth Chaganti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Reboot IT, Bangalore - Whats new in Server 2012 R2 Hyper-V</title>
      <link>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/reboot-it-bangalore-2014-session-slides-whats-new-in-server-2012-r2-hyper-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravikanthchaganti.com/blog/reboot-it-bangalore-2014-session-slides-whats-new-in-server-2012-r2-hyper-v/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the slides I used for my first session at the Reboot IT conference in Bangalore. We had over 130 attendees and the entire event was very well received.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;slideshare-embed&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; margin: 1.5rem auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;iframe&#xA;      src=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/3PSBj4JU4sFGIL&#34;&#xA;      style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: 1px solid #ccc; border-radius: 0.5rem;&#34;&#xA;      frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      marginheight=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;      scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&#xA;      allowfullscreen&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 5px;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a title=&#34;Whats new in Windows Server 2012 R2 Hyper-V&#34; href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/kanthrc/whats-new-in-windows-server-2012-r2-hyperv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Whats new in Windows Server 2012 R2 Hyper-V&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/kanthrc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ravikanth Chaganti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
