<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foundry on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/foundry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foundry on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/foundry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building persistent AI Agents with Microsoft Agent Framework and Microsoft Foundry</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-persistent-ai-agents-with-microsoft-agent-framework-and-microsoft-foundry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/building-persistent-ai-agents-with-microsoft-agent-framework-and-microsoft-foundry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my earlier post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-foundry-agents/&#34;&gt;Getting Started with Foundry Agents&lt;/a&gt;, I covered the basics of creating agents using the Azure AI Foundry Agents service and the &lt;code&gt;azure-ai-projects&lt;/code&gt; SDK. In another article in this series, we looked at creating Azure AI agents with Microsoft Agent Framework (MAF). Agents created with MAF are local only where MAF acts as the runtime. In this follow-up, we will examine how to create Foundry agents using MAF.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Foundry Agents</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-foundry-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-foundry-agents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Foundry (formerly Azure AI Foundry) is a unified system for building intelligent agents. It is a platform that provides models, tools, frameworks, and capabilities such as observability, guardrails, and enterprise-ready governance for building AI agents. With the Foundry Agent service, developers can develop agents locally and deploy them to different environments seamlessly, leveraging the building blocks provided by Microsoft Foundry. Foundry Agent service provides the runtime that manages conversations, orchestrates tool calls, and integrates with identify and observability systems. As discussed in the previous article, agents use LLMs to reason and make decisions. Agents use tools to perform actions. Agents can participate in workflows or interact with other agents to achieve a bigger goal. This is achieved by treating agents as composable units.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
