<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Agent Framework - Creating Microsoft Foundry Agents</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/microsoft-agent-framework-creating-microsoft-foundry-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/microsoft-agent-framework-creating-microsoft-foundry-agents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier article, we looked at a brief &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog//introduction-to-microsoft-agent-framework/&#34;&gt;introduction to the Microsoft Agent Framework&lt;/a&gt;. This framework combines the best parts of AutoGen and Semantic Kernel into a unified framework for building enterprise and production-ready AI agents. It supports various agent types, including Microsoft Foundry Agents. All agent types inherit from the common base class &lt;code&gt;AIAgent&lt;/code&gt; to provide a consistent interface.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Foundry agents are created using &lt;code&gt;AzureAIAgentClient&lt;/code&gt;. Let us start with an example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Foundry Agents</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-foundry-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/getting-started-with-foundry-agents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Foundry (formerly Azure AI Foundry) is a unified system for building intelligent agents. It is a platform that provides models, tools, frameworks, and capabilities such as observability, guardrails, and enterprise-ready governance for building AI agents. With the Foundry Agent service, developers can develop agents locally and deploy them to different environments seamlessly, leveraging the building blocks provided by Microsoft Foundry. Foundry Agent service provides the runtime that manages conversations, orchestrates tool calls, and integrates with identify and observability systems. As discussed in the previous article, agents use LLMs to reason and make decisions. Agents use tools to perform actions. Agents can participate in workflows or interact with other agents to achieve a bigger goal. This is achieved by treating agents as composable units.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/introduction-to-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/introduction-to-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been following the Microsoft ecosystem for agent and agentic workflow development and have evaluated frameworks such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/autogen&#34;&gt;AutoGen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/semantic-kernel&#34;&gt;Semantic Kernel&lt;/a&gt;. In the past, I have written &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/categories/autogen/&#34;&gt;briefly about AutoGen&lt;/a&gt;. I used Semantic Kernel, along with Azure AI Foundry, to experiment with a few enterprise-ready agentic scenarios. Both frameworks are useful in their own ways, and Semantic Kernel, with its enterprise-deployment readiness, became the go-to framework for many. Microsoft &lt;a href=&#34;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/introducing-microsoft-agent-framework-the-open-source-engine-for-agentic-ai-apps/&#34;&gt;announced plans to converge these frameworks&lt;/a&gt; into what it calls the Microsoft Agent Framework, which brings together the best parts of AutoGen and Semantic Kernel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
