<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skills on Ravikanth Chaganti</title>
    <link>https://ravichaganti.com/categories/skills/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Skills on Ravikanth Chaganti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ravichaganti.com/categories/skills/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google ADK - Agent Skills</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/google-adk-agent-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/google-adk-agent-skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every other week, we see a new framework claiming to simplify the development of AI agents. Thanks to the growing interest in agentic AI. Earlier this year, Google released its framework for developing agents, which it called the Agent Development Kit (ADK). In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/introduction-to-google-agent-development-kit/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we explored the basics of creating an &lt;code&gt;LlmAgent&lt;/code&gt; and running it using ADK&amp;rsquo;s built-in tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, we will dive into a powerful new feature in Google ADK: &lt;strong&gt;Agent Skills&lt;/strong&gt;. We will explore what Agent Skills are, why they matter, and how to implement a practical use case, an Azure Infrastructure as Code (IaC) agent that generates Bicep templates while strictly adhering to organizational governance rules.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magentic workflows in Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/magentic-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ravichaganti.com/blog/magentic-workflows-in-microsoft-agent-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seems like a season of &lt;a href=&#34;https://agentskills.io/home&#34;&gt;Agent Skills&lt;/a&gt; adoption. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/blog/google-adk-agent-skills/&#34;&gt;Google ADK implemented support for skills&lt;/a&gt; a couple of weeks ago, and it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/agent-framework/pull/4210&#34;&gt;Microsoft Agent Framework&amp;rsquo;s turn last week&lt;/a&gt;. In an earlier article in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ravichaganti.com/series/google-adk/&#34;&gt;Google ADK series&lt;/a&gt;, we implemented an IaC agent that leverages skills for generating Bicep templates that comply with organizational policies. In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we will explore how to implement the same in Microsoft Agent Framework (MAF).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike Google ADK, MAF has no inline skill support, so all skills must be implemented as directory skills. We will equip our agent with two skills:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
